<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Noted]]></title><description><![CDATA[Maximize Your Homelab Potential with Self-Hosting and Open-Source Solutions.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/</link><image><url>https://noted.lol/favicon.png</url><title>Noted</title><link>https://noted.lol/</link></image><generator>Ghost 6.2</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:01:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noted.lol/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI]]></title><description><![CDATA[Automate Restic backups in your homelab with Zerobyte’s dashboard. Create repos, schedule jobs, and restore files with confidence.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/zerobyte-restic-gui/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f2aff768607e00017be301</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Backup Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:04:46 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/zerobyte-restic-gui-noted.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/zerobyte-restic-gui-noted.jpg" alt="How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI"><p>If you manage a Linux box, your data is the thing you can&#x2019;t afford to lose. Whether you host it in the cloud, on a small VPS, or on bare metal in your homelab, one truth never changes. Something will fail eventually. Disks die, updates break, and people make mistakes. The only thing that saves you is a backup that actually works.</p><p>That is where <strong>Restic</strong> comes in. It is an open source backup system that is fast, efficient, secure, and built for real servers. It handles compression, deduplication, and encryption automatically, so you can focus on running your services instead of worrying about losing them.</p><hr><h3 id="what-is-zerobyte-gui">What is Zerobyte GUI?</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/nicotsx/zerobyte?ref=noted.lol">Zerobyte</a> is an open-source backup automation platform that wraps the Restic engine with a modern web interface, letting self-hosters create repositories, schedule jobs, and monitor backups from a dashboard rather than the CLI.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/backup-details.webp" class="kg-image" alt="How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI" loading="lazy" width="2000" height="963" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/backup-details.webp 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/backup-details.webp 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/backup-details.webp 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/11/backup-details.webp 2400w"></figure><h3 id="why-restic-plus-zerobyte-works">Why Restic plus Zerobyte works</h3><ul><li><strong>Restic</strong> handles the hard parts: encryption, deduplication, and multi&#x2011;backend support.</li><li><strong>Zerobyte</strong> handles the boring parts: job scheduling, credential management, and progress streaming.</li><li>Together you get secure, efficient backups with a usable control plane that&#x2019;s easy to hand off to someone else or revisit months later.</li></ul><h3 id="docker-compose-example">Docker Compose example</h3><p>Save this as <code>docker-compose.yml</code> and run <code>docker compose up -d</code>. Adjust paths, user IDs, and timezone to match your host.</p><pre><code class="language-yaml">services:
  zerobyte:
    image: nicotsx/zerobyte:latest
    container_name: zerobyte
    restart: unless-stopped
    ports:
      - &quot;4096:4096&quot;
    environment:
      - PUID=1000
      - PGID=1000
      - TZ=America/New_York
    volumes:
      - ./zerobyte-data:/app/data
      - /etc/rclone:/root/.config/rclone:ro
      - /srv/backups:/backups:rw
      - /etc/localtime:/etc/localtime:ro</code></pre><p><strong>Notes about the compose file</strong></p><ul><li><code>./zerobyte-data</code> stores Zerobyte metadata and should live on local disk for performance and fewer permission issues.</li><li><code>/etc/rclone</code> is optional. Mount your <code>rclone.conf</code> if you plan to use rclone remotes for cloud storage.</li><li><code>/srv/backups</code> is an example path you can use as a local Restic repository or staging area.</li><li>The UI listens on port <strong>4096</strong> by default. Visit <code>http://&lt;host&gt;:4096</code> after starting the container.</li></ul><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/add-volume.png" class="kg-image" alt="How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI" loading="lazy" width="1084" height="1172" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/add-volume.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/add-volume.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/add-volume.png 1084w"></figure><h3 id="post-deploy-checklist">Post deploy checklist</h3><ul><li>Create a repository in the UI. Choose local, S3&#x2011;compatible, or an rclone remote.</li><li>Mount the data you want to back up into the container and add those paths as sources in Zerobyte.</li><li>Create a job: pick include paths, add exclude patterns, set a schedule, and choose a retention policy.</li><li>Run the job manually once to validate credentials and the initial snapshot.</li><li>Keep CLI commands handy for recovery and troubleshooting. Example commands you&#x2019;ll want to know:</li></ul><pre><code class="language-bash"># initialize a local repo
export RESTIC_REPOSITORY=/srv/backups/restic-repo
export RESTIC_PASSWORD=&quot;strong-password&quot;
restic init

# create a backup
restic -r $RESTIC_REPOSITORY --password $RESTIC_PASSWORD backup /home /etc

# list snapshots
restic -r $RESTIC_REPOSITORY --password $RESTIC_PASSWORD snapshots

# forget and prune with a retention policy
restic -r $RESTIC_REPOSITORY --password $RESTIC_PASSWORD forget --prune \
  --keep-daily 7 --keep-weekly 4 --keep-monthly 12 --keep-yearly 3</code></pre><h3 id="practical-tips-retention-and-troubleshooting">Practical tips retention and troubleshooting</h3><ul><li>Test restores regularly. A backup that can&#x2019;t be restored is useless. Do a small restore weekly and a larger one monthly.</li><li>Keep Zerobyte metadata local. Putting the app data on a flaky network share invites permission and performance headaches.</li><li>Use rclone for cloud flexibility. If you want offsite copies, mount your <code>rclone.conf</code> into the container and use rclone remotes so you&#x2019;re not locked to one provider.</li><li>Expect the first backup to be heavy. Initial snapshots are I/O and bandwidth intensive. Schedule them during low&#x2011;usage windows.</li><li>Don&#x2019;t rely on a single copy. Keep at least one independent offline copy (external disk) for critical data.</li><li>Monitor and update. Zerobyte adds a web app layer. Keep the container updated and watch logs for failed jobs.</li><li>When things go wrong: use the Restic CLI to inspect snapshots, run <code>restic check</code> to validate repos, and export logs from Zerobyte for debugging.</li></ul><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>Restic gives you the reliability and safety you need. Zerobyte gives you the convenience to use it without living in the terminal. Together they make a practical, low maintenance backup setup for homelabs and small servers.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://github.com/nicotsx/zerobyte?ref=noted.lol"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">GitHub - nicotsx/zerobyte: Backup automation for self-hosters</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Backup automation for self-hosters. Contribute to nicotsx/zerobyte development by creating an account on GitHub.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/pinned-octocat-093da3e6fa40-37.svg" alt="How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">GitHub</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">nicotsx</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/2d0f4581-1187-485d-bbf8-50a20f3e408c" alt="How to Back Up Your Server the Smart Way with Restic and Zerobyte GUI" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Journiv: Your Thoughts Deserve to Be Remembered]]></title><description><![CDATA[You've self-hosted your photos with Immich. Your documents live in Nextcloud. Your passwords are safely tucked away in Vaultwarden. You've taken control of your digital life, one Docker container or LXC at a time. But what about your thoughts and memories?]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/journiv/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">692645ea68607e00017c5412</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Note-taking & Editors]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Journiv App]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:05:28 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/journiv-self-hosted-journaling-noted.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="Journiv: Your Thoughts Deserve to Be Remembered">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/journiv-self-hosted-journaling-noted.jpg" alt="Journiv: Your Thoughts Deserve to Be Remembered"><p>You&apos;ve self-hosted your photos with Immich. Your documents live in Nextcloud. Your passwords are safely tucked away in Vaultwarden. You&apos;ve taken control of your digital life, one Docker container or LXC at a time.</p><p>But there&apos;s one type of data that&apos;s more personal than all of these, and it&apos;s probably either not completely in your control or, worse, not captured at all.</p><p>Your thoughts. Your reflections. Your memories of the moments that matter most.</p><h2 id="the-self-hosting-gap-nobody-talks-about">The Self-Hosting Gap Nobody Talks About</h2><p>We obsess over server specs, debate PostgreSQL vs SQLite, and carefully architect our home labs for reliability and privacy. We containerize everything, back up religiously, and take pride in owning our data.</p><p>But when it comes to preserving our thoughts and memories? Most of us either hand over our most intimate reflections to third-party journaling apps or try to mold them into self-hosted note-taking apps never designed for this purpose.</p><h2 id="when-convenient-becomes-uncomfortable">When &quot;Convenient&quot; Becomes Uncomfortable</h2><p>A few years ago, I was scrolling through hundreds of photos of my toddlers, thinking about all the tiny moments I wanted to remember: the first clumsy dance, how they mangle new words, the small adventures that make up childhood.</p><p>I started looking for a journaling app to capture these stories, something to preserve not just the photos, but the context, the emotions, the narrative that makes memories complete.</p><p>Every journal solution I found had the same problem: third-party servers, vendor lock-in, inconvenient and incomplete export formats. My children&apos;s memories, my personal reflections, my family&apos;s stories - all locked away, profiled, and out of my control.</p><p>As a developer who loves self-hosts everything, this felt wrong.</p><p>But when I looked for self-hosted alternatives, I found something surprising: there weren&apos;t any. Not real ones.</p><h2 id="the-tools-that-almost-worked">The Tools That Almost Worked</h2><p>I tried the usual self-hosted note-taking apps, excellent tools that many in this community already use. But they&apos;re note-taking applications, not journals. They lack the features that make journaling meaningful:</p><ul><li>No &quot;On This Day&quot; memories to surface past entries</li><li>No writing prompts for when you&apos;re facing a blank page</li><li>No mood tracking to see patterns over months</li><li>No rich media integration with photo libraries</li><li>No journaling-specific insights or analytics</li><li>No built-in calendar views of your writing consistency</li></ul><p>These tools are built for information capture, not reflection. For storing facts, not preserving memories and feelings.</p><p>I needed something different. Something that understood the difference between a note and a memory.</p><p>So I <a href="https://journiv.com/blog/the-story-behind-journiv?ref=noted.lol">built it</a>.</p><h2 id="meet-journiv-journaling-built-for-self-hosters">Meet Journiv: Journaling Built for Self-Hosters</h2><p>Journiv is what I wish had existed when I started looking: a purpose-built journaling platform designed from the ground up for self-hosting.</p><p>It&apos;s not trying to be everything to everyone. It&apos;s trying to do one thing exceptionally well: be a journal you can own completely.</p><p>Your journal entries are deeply personal. They contain your fears, hopes, struggles, and growth. With Journiv, they stay on your server, under your control, <a href="https://journiv.com/blog/privacy-in-journaling?ref=noted.lol">private by design</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/demo-dark.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Journiv: Your Thoughts Deserve to Be Remembered" loading="lazy" width="2000" height="1142" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/demo-dark.jpg 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/demo-dark.jpg 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/demo-dark.jpg 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/11/demo-dark.jpg 2400w"></figure><h3 id="features-that-actually-matter">Features That Actually Matter</h3><p>Beyond privacy and longevity, Journiv includes everything you&apos;d expect from a modern journaling platform:</p><ul><li><strong>Multiple journals</strong> for different aspects of life (personal, work, gratitude, projects)</li><li><strong>Writing prompts</strong> to spark reflection when you&apos;re stuck</li><li><strong>Mood and activity tracking</strong> with beautiful visualizations</li><li><strong>Rich text support</strong> without sacrificing Markdown simplicity (coming soon)</li><li><strong>Full-text search</strong> across all entries with powerful filtering</li><li><strong>Media uploads</strong> with automatic thumbnail generation</li><li><strong>Calendar views</strong> to track your writing consistency (coming soon)</li><li><strong>Analytics and insights</strong> to understand patterns in your life</li><li><a href="https://journiv.com/blog/journiv-immich-integration?ref=noted.lol"><strong>Immich integration</strong></a> to link journal entries with your photo library</li><li><strong>Tag system</strong> to organize and find entries years later</li><li><strong>Standalone viewer</strong>: Export your data, open the HTML file in any browser. No server, no internet required</li><li><strong>Import/Export</strong>: Export and import your journals natively in the app for backup and restore. Or bring your Day One journals to Journiv.</li></ul><p>All of this is fast, lightweight, beautiful, and designed not to get in your way.</p><h2 id="the-installation-youd-expect">The Installation You&apos;d Expect</h2><p>If you&apos;re reading Noted, you already know the drill. Here&apos;s what you need:</p><pre><code class="language-yaml">services:
  journiv:
    image: swalabtech/journiv-app:latest
    container_name: journiv
    ports:
      - &quot;8000:8000&quot;
    environment:
      - SECRET_KEY=your-secret-key-here # your key
      - DOMAIN_NAME=192.168.1.1 # your domain
    volumes:
      - journiv_data:/data
    restart: unless-stopped

volumes:
  journiv_data:
</code></pre><p>That&apos;s it. Run <code>docker compose up -d</code> (or use <a href="https://journiv.com/docs/installation/quick-start?ref=noted.lol#tab-podman">Podman</a>, if that&apos;s your thing) and you&apos;re up.</p><p>Full installation docs are at <a href="https://journiv.com/docs/installation?ref=noted.lol">journiv.com/docs/installation</a>.</p><p>Want OIDC with Authentik or Keycloak? Supported out of the box. Want to run it behind Traefik or Caddy? Works perfectly. Need user management? You have it.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="150" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nKoUh7VP-eE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Journiv - Private Journal App Web Client Demo"></iframe></figure><h2 id="why-this-matters-even-if-you-dont-journal">Why This Matters (Even If You Don&apos;t Journal)</h2><p>Maybe you&apos;re thinking: &quot;I&apos;m not a journal person. Why should I care?&quot;</p><p>Fair question. Here&apos;s why:</p><p>I wasn&apos;t a &quot;journal person&quot; either until I tried it seriously. Now I can&apos;t imagine not having a record of my thoughts, decisions, and growth over time. The insights you gain from reviewing entries from months or years ago are genuinely valuable.</p><p>Moreover, Journiv is for everyone:</p><ul><li><strong>Travelers</strong> who want to remember not just where they went, but who they were when they got there</li><li><strong>Families</strong> who want to preserve the small moments, not just the holidays</li><li><strong>Anyone</strong> who&apos;s ever looked at a photo and thought, &quot;There&apos;s so much more to this story&quot;</li><li><strong>People</strong> who believe privacy matters and memories deserve protection</li></ul><h2 id="try-it-yourself">Try It Yourself</h2><p>Journiv is in active development with a fully functional backend, web interface, and mobile apps launching soon.</p><p>If you&apos;ve been looking for a way to capture your thoughts and memories or to capture the stories behind your photos and videos without compromising on privacy or data ownership, give it a try.</p><p><strong>Installation</strong>: <a href="https://journiv.com/docs/installation?ref=noted.lol">journiv.com/docs/installation</a><br><strong>Source Code</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/journiv/journiv-app?ref=noted.lol">github.com/journiv/journiv-app</a><br><strong>Community</strong>: <a href="https://discord.com/invite/CuEJ8qft46?ref=noted.lol">Discord</a> | <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Journiv/?ref=noted.lol">Reddit</a><br><strong>Docs</strong>: <a href="https://journiv.com/docs?ref=noted.lol">journiv.com/docs</a></p><p>Your memories deserve more. They deserve to be yours, forever.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox]]></title><description><![CDATA[ProxMenux Manager simplifies Proxmox administration with a menu driven CLI and a modern web dashboard for real time monitoring of VMs storage and hardware.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/proxmenux-manager/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6920a21368607e00017c3c11</guid><category><![CDATA[Homelab]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:16:09 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-noted.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-noted.jpg" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox"><p>If you run Proxmox and have ever sighed while clicking through nested menus or pasting commands into a shell, ProxMenux feels like the friend who finally shows up with a better way. It wraps the chores you do every day into a simple guided menu so you can get things done without hunting through the web UI or memorizing fragile one liners. It is open source and menu driven and it helps you move fast while avoiding the small mistakes that slow you down.</p><h3 id="what-it-is-and-why-it-matters">What it is and why it matters</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/MacRimi/ProxMenux?ref=noted.lol">ProxMenux Manager</a> offers a menu driven approach to virtual machine and container operations storage tweaks network helpers and post install tasks. It runs on a node and exposes grouped actions such as creating a VM creating a container cloning exporting disk images and managing templates. Each menu item is an opinionated sequence of checks and commands that aim for safe defaults while letting you tweak important options.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-noted.png" class="kg-image" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" loading="lazy" width="967" height="515" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-noted.png 967w"></figure><p>The core idea is simple. Take the handful of tasks you repeat across nodes and make them fast and reproducible. The payoff is not just time saved but fewer mistakes and easier onboarding when someone else needs to follow the same steps.</p><h3 id="the-power-behind-the-cli-tools">The power behind the CLI tools</h3><p>You install ProxMenux Manager on a test node then you launch it and you are greeted by a clean menu. The menus are terse and direct. Pick the operation answer a few prompts and let the script run the checks and the commands. The feedback is text first and pragmatic. If something went wrong you get the explicit command that failed and a short tail of the log so you know where to look.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-disk-noted.png" class="kg-image" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" loading="lazy" width="875" height="483" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-disk-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-menu-disk-noted.png 875w"></figure><p>Two benefits are immediate. First the operation speed increases because the route from intention to outcome is shorter. Second the human error surface shrinks because the menu enforces validation and consistent flags. When you manage multiple hosts the difference compounds quickly.</p><h3 id="the-added-web-interface-is-a-bonus">The added web interface is a bonus</h3><p>The new web interface is a welcome bonus that complements the menu driven CLI with a visual, browser friendly view of your infrastructure. It gives you real time metrics for CPU, memory, storage, network, and SMART health, and it surfaces those signals in a clean dashboard so you can spot problems at a glance.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-lxc-containers-noted.png" width="1917" height="760" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-lxc-containers-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-lxc-containers-noted.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-lxc-containers-noted.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-lxc-containers-noted.png 1917w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-overview-noted.png" width="1920" height="845" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-overview-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-overview-noted.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-overview-noted.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-overview-noted.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div></div></div></figure><p>The web view does not replace the CLI, it extends it, making it easy to move from a visual summary into the guided menu when you need to take action. For home labs and production clusters alike, the dashboard speeds situational awareness and reduces the number of times you need to switch contexts to resolve an issue.</p><h3 id="use-it-as-a-pwa-behind-reverse-proxy">Use it as a PWA behind reverse proxy</h3><p>With built in authentication and 2FA, we have a dual layer security option giving us more peace of mind when exposing this to use as a Progressive Web App. And boy does it kick some serious butt!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7682.PNG" width="1284" height="2778" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/IMG_7682.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/IMG_7682.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7682.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7681.PNG" width="1284" height="2778" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/IMG_7681.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/IMG_7681.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7681.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div></div><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7680.PNG" width="1284" height="2778" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/IMG_7680.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/IMG_7680.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7680.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7679.PNG" width="1284" height="2778" loading="lazy" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/IMG_7679.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/IMG_7679.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/IMG_7679.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div></div></div></figure><p>Use the ProxMenux web dashboard as a progressive web app to control LXCs and VMs from your phone.</p><h3 id="install-proxmenux-manager-with-one-command">Install ProxMenux Manager with one command</h3><p>Using this single bash install command, you can have ProxMenux Manger up and running lickity split! Run the command in your Proxmox node terminal.</p><pre><code class="language-bash">bash -c &quot;$(wget -qO- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MacRimi/ProxMenux/main/install_proxmenux.sh)&quot;</code></pre><p>Follow the on screen dialogue and wait about 3 minutes for of the dependencies to install.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-noted.png" class="kg-image" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" loading="lazy" width="742" height="893" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/proxmenux-manager-cli-noted.png 742w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>To access the web interface you can visit the IP of the Proxmox node on port 8008.</p><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>I like this a lot and I will use it as a PWA for quick access from my phone. It gives me the speed of the CLI when I need it and a friendly dashboard when I just want a glance. Installing the PWA and placing it behind a reverse proxy with HTTPS and solid auth means I can manage LXCs and VMs safely from anywhere without fumbling through the web UI or memorizing commands.</p><p>I encourage you to read more about ProxMenux Manager and give it a star on their <a href="https://github.com/MacRimi/ProxMenux?ref=noted.lol">Github repo</a>!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://github.com/MacRimi/ProxMenux?ref=noted.lol"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">GitHub - MacRimi/ProxMenux: ProxMenux An Interactive Menu for Proxmox VE Management</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">ProxMenux An Interactive Menu for Proxmox VE Management - MacRimi/ProxMenux</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/pinned-octocat-093da3e6fa40-36.svg" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">GitHub</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">MacRimi</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/1ded6f1c-0184-4636-96c3-04a3fa01c8fc" alt="ProxMenux Manager: Menu Driven CLI and Real Time Web Dashboard for Proxmox" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Discover five simple and creative ways to use n8n for automation. Build small workflows that save time, stay organized, and make everyday tasks easier.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/n8n-5-ideas-for-automation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f6778868607e00017bf76a</guid><category><![CDATA[n8n]]></category><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Automation Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:09:06 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-wokflows-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-wokflows-noted.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><p>There is something rewarding about seeing a process run on its own. A few nodes linked together, and suddenly a small part of your workflow just works. That is the beauty of n8n. It gives you space to connect tools, move data, and build systems that save time without adding complexity.</p><p>Here are five creative ways to put n8n to work.</p><h3 id="1-self-running-homelab-video-encoder-bash-n8n-for-scheduled-atomic-mp4-conversions">1. Self-running homelab video encoder: Bash + n8n for scheduled, atomic MP4 conversions</h3><p>A compact, practical homelab project that finds non&#x2011;MP4 videos, converts them to MP4 (GPU-aware when available), handles subtitles, logs per-file results, and posts a JSON summary into n8n for scheduling, storage, and notifications.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/self-running-video-encoder-bash-n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Learn a hands on n8n homelab project that automates media conversion, frees up space with smart compression and cleanup, and gives you a fun rainy day tinkering task.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-42.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-media-conversion.jpg" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="2-automated-rsync-backups-to-synology-with-n8n-orchestration">2. Automated rsync backups to Synology with n8n orchestration</h3><p>A lightweight n8n workflow that runs rsync against a mounted Synology Samba share, parses rsync stats into a compact summary, and sends instant ntfy notifications so your NAS stays mirrored and you always know what changed.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/n8n-fle-sync-with-rsync/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Automate seamless file backups from your server to a Synology NAS using n8n, rsync, and Samba. This workflow keeps your data mirrored, sends instant notifications, and gives you a clear view of your storage every time it runs.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-43.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-file-sync-noted.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="3-system-log-dashboard-and-ssh-alert-workflow-with-n8n">3. System log dashboard and SSH alert workflow with n8n</h3><p>A compact n8n project that pulls journalctl, auth logs, dmesg, and network stats into a polished HTML dashboard with live counts, copyable error entries, and a conditional alert that notifies you on failed SSH login spikes.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/system-log-dashboard-n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Learn how to build a clean system log dashboard and smart SSH alert workflow using n8n. This guide walks through real log parsing, visual dashboards, and notifications when login attempts fail.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-44.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-system-logs-dashboard-workflow-noted.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="4-hdd-health-watchdog-n8n-smartmontools-with-ntfy-push-alerts">4. HDD health watchdog: n8n + SmartMonTools with ntfy push alerts</h3><p>A simple n8n workflow that runs smartctl over SSH each morning, parses drive health, temperature, reallocated and pending sectors, and pushes concise ntfy notifications (with per&#x2011;drive details) so you see failing or marginal disks before they become catastrophic.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/hdd-health-alerts-using-n8n-and-ntfy/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Self-Hosted HDD Health Alerts using n8n and ntfy</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Monitor your drives with n8n and SmartMonTools and get instant notifications with ntfy for real-time health and temperature updates.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-45.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-ntfy-noted-1.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="5-self%E2%80%91hosted-n8n-rss-to-discord-notifier-with-easy-webhook-delivery">5. Self&#x2011;hosted n8n RSS to Discord notifier with easy webhook delivery</h3><p>A minimal n8n workflow that polls RSS feeds, formats new-post entries, and posts them to a Discord channel via webhook. Includes Docker Compose install tips, credential handling, a test flow, and suggestions for extensions like summarization or archiving.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/n8n-rss-discord-notifications/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Self-Hosting n8n for RSS Notifications to Discord</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Learn how to use n8n to send RSS feed updates directly to Discord. A simple self-hosted workflow that keeps you notified whenever new articles are published on your favorite websites.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-46.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-self-hosted-rss-to-discord-noted.png" alt="5 Creative Ways to Use n8n for Automation" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>The best automations are the ones that make everyday tasks easier and more reliable. Start with small n8n flows that solve a single repetitive step, like fetching logs, sending a notification, or syncing a folder. As you add a few of these you will begin to see repeatable patterns and bottlenecks across your routine that can be consolidated or eliminated. Focus on clear inputs and outputs and conservative alerts so failures are easy to find and fix.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Practical Self-Hosting to Survive Cloudflare Outages]]></title><description><![CDATA[How to make your site resilient when Cloudflare fails: compact self-hosting tactics, fallback status pages, dual DNS, and automated failover.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/resilient-self-hosting-cloudflare-fallback/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">691c884868607e00017c3370</guid><category><![CDATA[How To]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Cedric]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:05:24 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/cloudflare-outtAGE.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/cloudflare-outtAGE.png" alt="Practical Self-Hosting to Survive Cloudflare Outages"><p>When a single vendor that sits between users and sites fails, a lot of things stop working at once. That &quot;internal server error on Cloudflare&#x2019;s network , please try again in a few minutes&quot; is the modern equivalent of a fuse blowing in the power box of the internet.</p><p>If you run things yourself (or want to), this is where self-hosting earns its stripes: you can design for fewer single points of failure, clearer failover, and predictable outages you control. Below are clear, pragmatic moves to make your stack survive when someone else&#x2019;s network trips.</p><h3 id="core-strategy-to-reduce-choke-points-own-the-fallback">Core strategy to reduce choke points, own the fallback</h3><ul><li><strong>Know your critical path.</strong> List what must work for your product to deliver value (API, static assets, auth). Anything off that list is &quot;nice to have&quot; during an outage.</li><li><strong>Split responsibilities.</strong> Don&#x2019;t put DNS, CDN, reverse proxy, and WAF all behind one managed layer if you can afford alternatives.</li><li><strong>Plan simple fallbacks.</strong> A basic static HTML status page served from a second origin (S3, object storage, GitHub Pages) keeps users informed and preserves trust.</li></ul><h3 id="practical-architecture-patterns">Practical architecture patterns</h3><ul><li><strong>Multi-origin static hosting</strong><ul><li>Primary: Cloudflare + origin.</li><li>Secondary: S3 / GitHub Pages / Netlify as a read-only origin for static assets and a status page.</li><li>How it helps: Static content and status survive if the proxy layer dies.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Dual DNS / failover</strong><ul><li>Use DNS with short TTLs and automatic failover (Route 53, Cloud DNS) or run a script that updates your A/AAAA records if health checks fail.</li><li>Keep a secondary authoritative DNS provider so a DNS provider outage won&#x2019;t take you down.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Multiple CDNs or Reverse Proxies</strong><ul><li>Mirror critical assets across two CDNs or use a small self-hosted reverse proxy (Traefik, Caddy, nginx) on a different network provider.</li><li>Use DNS-based traffic steering or a health-checking script to switch origins.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Tunnel + direct IP fallback</strong><ul><li>If you expose services via tunnels (cloudflared/ngrok), maintain a direct public IP + firewall rule path for emergencies.</li><li>Keep an automated script to flip A records to the direct IP if the tunnel health check fails.</li><li>Consider lightweight tunnel/reverse-proxy alternatives such as <a href="https://noted.lol/pangolin/">Pangolin</a> as an option for redundancy or self-hosted ingress; it can be another path to expose services without relying solely on one vendor.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Local caching and client resilience</strong><ul><li>Cache aggressively on the client and edge for assets and API responses that can be stale for short periods.</li><li>Use Service Workers for progressive offline behavior and a cached &quot;we&#x2019;re having issues&quot; page.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="operations-and-automation-you-can-implement-today">Operations and automation you can implement today</h3><ul><li><strong>Health checks + automatic remediation</strong><ul><li>Run periodic synthetic checks for web, API, and TLS. If checks fail, run remediation scripts: rotate DNS, restart proxies, or switch to a failover origin.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Simple failover script (concept)</strong><ul><li>Health check &#x2192; if FAILED then update DNS via provider API &#x2192; notify on Slack/email and log everything to /var/log/failover.log.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Certificate automation</strong><ul><li>Keep ACME clients (certbot, lego) configured for both primary and fallback origins; store TLS certs in a shared, versioned secret store.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Observability</strong><ul><li>Push logs and short JSON status blobs to an external, independent storage (S3/Backblaze) to preserve audit trails if your site is down.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Runbook</strong><ul><li>One page, copy-paste commands for: flip DNS, bring up direct origin, revoke/issue cert, rotate tunnel, tail last 200 lines of proxy logs. Store it in the repo and on a static status page.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="defensive-defaults-for-resilient-self-hosting">Defensive defaults for resilient self-hosting</h3><ul><li>Keep TTLs low for records you expect to switch quickly; keep them higher for truly stable records to avoid cache thrash.</li><li>Design endpoints so feature degradation is graceful: API v2 returns cached &quot;stale-but-served&quot; payloads when backend is unreachable.</li><li>Use immutable infrastructure for critical pieces (baked images, IaC) so failover is predictable and repeatable.</li><li>Limit blast radius: run WAF/proxy in front of disposable services and keep core auth and payment services on minimal, separate stacks.</li></ul><h3 id="quick-checklist-to-survive-the-next-big-provider-outage">Quick checklist to survive the next big provider outage</h3><ol><li><strong>Status page hosted outside your primary stack</strong></li><li><strong>Secondary static origin with synced assets</strong></li><li><strong>Dual DNS providers or DNS failover automation</strong></li><li><strong>Health checks + scripted remediation (logs to disk and external store)</strong></li><li><strong>TLS certs ready for both primary and failover hosts</strong></li><li><strong>Direct-IP access path if tunnel/CDN fails</strong></li><li><strong>Optional: alternate tunnel or ingress like Pangolin for extra redundancy</strong></li><li><strong>Runbook and one-shot debug scripts in the repo</strong></li></ol><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>Self-hosting is not a yes or no decision. It is a series of choices about how much vendor risk you accept and how much operational work you want on your plate. If you want your site to show something when Cloudflare hiccups, skip the heroic midnight tinkering and build a few small tested fallbacks now. Start with easy wins like a static status page, a secondary DNS, and a health check that can flip records automatically. When the next CDN blip happens you will be calm, your users will see a helpful message, and your ops will look deliberate instead of panicked.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fixing Docker’s Network Problem Before It Breaks Yours]]></title><description><![CDATA[Docker’s default network settings can consume your IP space and cause conflicts on your home network. Learn how to adjust the default address pool to prevent overlapping subnets and fix the “no available networks” error before it happens.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/fixing-docker-network-problem/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69020e0b68607e00017c0b34</guid><category><![CDATA[Homelab]]></category><category><![CDATA[How To]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:33:45 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/docker-networking-not-enough-networks-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/docker-networking-not-enough-networks-noted.png" alt="Fixing Docker&#x2019;s Network Problem Before It Breaks Yours"><p>Most people install Docker and never think twice about how it manages networks. Containers spin up, connect to each other, and everything seems to work perfectly. But Docker&#x2019;s defaults hide a quiet problem that can break your setup over time.</p><p>Every time Docker creates a network, it reserves a large block of IP addresses from a shared pool. Eventually that pool either overlaps with your home network or runs out entirely, triggering the dreaded &#x201C;could not find an available, non-overlapping IPv4 address pool&#x201D; error.</p><p>The fix is simple, but it is something every self-hoster should do before it becomes a problem.</p><h3 id="when-docker-uses-too-much-space">When Docker Uses Too Much Space</h3><p>By default, Docker uses the address range 172.16.0.0 through 172.31.255.255, which is known as a twelve block. Each time a new network is created, Docker takes a large portion of that space, known as a twenty subnet. That means every new network gets more than four thousand usable IP addresses even if it only needs a few.</p><p>Over time, as you add and remove containers or create new stacks, Docker continues to reserve those large subnets. Once it runs low on space in the original range, it begins using addresses from 192.168.0.0, which many home networks already depend on. This can lead to IP conflicts and strange problems that seem to appear for no reason at all.</p><p>You might suddenly lose access to your NAS, or your router might start acting up because Docker assigned an overlapping address. It can be confusing and frustrating to troubleshoot if you do not know what is happening.</p><h3 id="the-%E2%80%9Cnot-enough-networks%E2%80%9D-error">The &#x201C;Not Enough Networks&#x201D; Error</h3><p>If you ever see an error like</p><blockquote>
<p>&quot;could not find an available, non-overlapping IPv4 address pool among the defaults to assign to the network&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That is Docker telling you it has completely run out of usable subnets from its default pool. It has tried to create a new network but every possible address range it knows about is already in use or overlaps with something else.</p><p>This error is common when Docker keeps carving large twenty subnets out of its twelve block. Eventually there is no room left. Adjusting the pool size fixes this completely.</p><h3 id="the-simple-fix">The Simple Fix</h3><p>There is an easy way to stop all of this from happening. The goal is to tell Docker to take smaller pieces of the same address range so it does not consume unnecessary space. Instead of reserving a twenty subnet each time, you can change it to use a twenty-four subnet. That change means Docker still uses the same twelve range, but it only takes smaller slices with about two hundred fifty-four usable addresses per network.</p><p>To make the adjustment, open or create the file <code>/etc/docker/daemon.json</code> and add the following configuration:</p><pre><code class="language-json">{
  &quot;log-level&quot;: &quot;warn&quot;,
  &quot;log-driver&quot;: &quot;json-file&quot;,
  &quot;log-opts&quot;: {
    &quot;max-size&quot;: &quot;10m&quot;,
    &quot;max-file&quot;: &quot;5&quot;
  },
  &quot;default-address-pools&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;base&quot;: &quot;172.16.0.0/12&quot;,
      &quot;size&quot;: 24
    }
  ]
}</code></pre><p>Save the file and restart Docker. Then take down any active compose stacks and bring them up again so their networks are recreated using the new subnet size.</p><p>Once you have done this, Docker will still use the same twelve address block, but instead of handing out a large twenty every time, it will now allocate smaller and more reasonable twenty-four networks.</p><p>This change also fixes the &#x201C;not enough networks&#x201D; error. By resetting the address pool, you give Docker fresh room to create new networks without conflict. If you have already hit that error, prune unused networks with</p><pre><code>docker network prune</code></pre><p>then restart the service. After that, everything will work normally again.</p><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>Docker is powerful, but its defaults were never meant for a small home server. Changing the address pool once saves you from those strange network bugs that always show up at the worst time. It keeps Docker in its own lane and lets the rest of your setup run without surprise conflicts.</p><p>It is one of those fixes that feels minor but makes a big difference. You do it once, forget about it, and everything just works the way it should.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/docker-networking-made-simple/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Docker Networking Made Simple: What Every Beginner Needs to Know</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Docker is amazing until your containers need to talk to each other. Suddenly, terms like bridge, host, and overlay show up, and it feels like learning a foreign language. Don&#x2019;t worry, it&#x2019;s simpler than it seems. Why Containers Can&#x2019;t Just Chat Think of each container as a</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-41.png" alt="Fixing Docker&#x2019;s Network Problem Before It Breaks Yours"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/docker-networking-beginners-noted.png" alt="Fixing Docker&#x2019;s Network Problem Before It Breaks Yours" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI]]></title><description><![CDATA[A tidy, practical web UI for managing host cron jobs and runnable scripts built with Next.js TypeScript and Tailwind and packaged to run from Docker for quick deployment.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/cronmaster/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6916140968607e00017c28da</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Web Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:42:38 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/self-hosted-cronmaster-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/self-hosted-cronmaster-noted.png" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI"><p>If you have ever SSH&#x2019;d into a server just to tweak a crontab entry, squinted at a wall of asterisk syntax, or copy-pasted a script into a bin folder hoping it runs, Cronmaster is here to make that whole experience feel more streamlined.</p><h3 id="what-is-cronmaster">What is Cronmaster?</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/fccview/cronmaster?ref=noted.lol">Cronmaster</a> gives you a clean responsive interface for managing cron jobs and runnable scripts on your host machine. It is built with Next.js, TypeScript, and Tailwind and ships as a Docker container that is surprisingly easy to drop into your homelab.</p><h3 id="what-it-does">What it does</h3><ol><li><strong>Cron job management</strong> View create clone delete jobs and add descriptions with quick presets for common schedules.</li><li><strong>Script management</strong> Create edit clone and store Bash scripts that the UI can execute from cron entries with helpful snippets for composition.</li><li><strong>System info</strong> Hostname IP uptime memory CPU and GPU details are visible so you do not need to jump to the shell.</li><li><strong>Container packaging</strong> Docker first with options for host socket host PID persistent data mounts and multi architecture images.</li></ol><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/home.png" class="kg-image" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI" loading="lazy" width="1605" height="932" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/home.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/home.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/home.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/home.png 1605w"></figure><h3 id="cronmaster-installation-with-docker">Cronmaster Installation with Docker</h3><p>Here&#x2019;s a short and practical Docker Compose setup for Cronmaster:</p><pre><code class="language-yaml">version: &quot;3.8&quot;
services:
  cronmaster:
    image: fccview/cronmaster:latest
    container_name: cronmaster
    ports:
      - &quot;3000:3000&quot;
    environment:
      - AUTH_PASSWORD=yourpassword
      - HOST_PROJECT_DIR=/data/scripts
      - HOST_CRONTAB_USER=root
    volumes:
      - /your/host/scripts:/data/scripts
      - /etc/crontab:/etc/crontab:ro
      - /etc/cron.d:/etc/cron.d:ro
      - /var/spool/cron:/var/spool/cron
    pid: &quot;host&quot;
    privileged: true</code></pre><p>Replace <code>/your/host/scripts</code> with the actual path where you want scripts to live. </p><p>Then run:</p><pre><code class="language-txt">docker-compose up -d</code></pre><p>That&#x2019;s it. You&#x2019;ll have a web UI for cron jobs at <code>http://localhost:3000</code>.</p><h3 id="tradeoffs-and-operational-notes">Tradeoffs and operational notes</h3><ol><li><strong>Privilege model</strong> Real time crontab edits require root and direct file access when the app runs in a container. That provides power and convenience at the cost of host security considerations.</li><li><strong>Data location</strong> Scripts created via the UI live under the configured project directory. Moving that folder will break any crontab entries that reference UI managed paths.</li><li><strong>Host parity</strong> Commands that succeed when run as root on the host may fail when executed through the container if environmental parity is not matched. The repo encourages issue reports for edge cases.</li></ol><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/backup.png" class="kg-image" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI" loading="lazy" width="1601" height="930" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/backup.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/backup.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/backup.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/backup.png 1601w"></figure><h3 id="who-should-use-it">Who should use it</h3><ol><li>Homelab operators and small server admins who want a visual low friction way to manage scheduled tasks and test scripts.</li><li>Teams that need a readable UI for cron audits and quick cloning of similar jobs.</li><li>Avoid this if strict least privilege policies are mandatory unless you run the app directly on the host outside of Docker.</li></ol><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>There are tradeoffs. Running in a container means you need root access and host mounts to edit crontabs in real time. That is powerful but not ideal for hardened environments. If you want to avoid that, you can run Cronmaster directly on the host using yarn install and start. Also, scripts created in the UI live under a fixed path. If you move that folder, your jobs will break. The author encourages issue reports for commands that work on the host but fail through the app.</p><p>Be sure to give the Cronmaster project a star on the <a href="https://github.com/fccview/cronmaster?ref=noted.lol">Github repo</a>!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/tag/n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">n8n - Noted</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">I&#x2019;m obsessed with n8n so I made it a category. Here&#x2019;s all things related to n8n.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-40.png" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8-systemlog-workflow-8.png" alt="Cronmaster: Self-Hosted Cron Control with a Clean UI" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 10MB Discord Limit Drove Me to Build a Self-Hosted GPU Video Compressor]]></title><description><![CDATA[Set-it-and-forget video compression for your homelab: 8mb.local is a single Docker container with a SvelteKit UI, GPU-accelerated encoding, and target-size-first compression.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/8mb-local/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6913854168607e00017c250d</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted File Conversion]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jason Selsley]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:43:39 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/article5.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/article5.png" alt="The 10MB Discord Limit Drove Me to Build a Self-Hosted GPU Video Compressor"><p>We&#x2019;ve all been there. You have a clip you want to share on Discord, but it&#x2019;s 40MB. The upload limit stares back at you: 10MB.</p><p>So begins the ritual. You open HandBrake, fiddle with presets, guess at a bitrate, export, check the file size... 10.2MB. Rinse and repeat. Or perhaps you&apos;re a command-line warrior, trying to remember the exact <code>ffmpeg</code> incantation to hit your target. I was so tired of this process I decided to build a solution for myself, and I thought the self-hosting community might find it useful, too.</p><p>It&#x2019;s called <a href="https://github.com/JMS1717/8mb.local?ref=noted.lol" rel="noopener"><strong>8mb.local</strong></a>, and it&#x2019;s a self-hosted, &quot;fire-and-forget&quot; video compressor built to solve this exact problem.</p><p>It&#x2019;s all packed into a single Docker container. You get a clean SvelteKit web UI, a FastAPI backend, and a Celery worker queue. You just drag and drop your file, choose a target size (like 8MB, 25MB, or 50MB), and let it run.</p><h2 id="what-is-8mblocal">What is 8mb.local?</h2><p>The goal of <code>8mb.local</code> is to make video compression simple, fast, and smart. It&#x2019;s not just a basic <code>ffmpeg</code> wrapper; it&#x2019;s a full-featured web UI designed for a homelab environment designed to be compatible with a wide range of system configurations  out of the box.</p><p>The real magic is that it automatically detects and uses your GPU for much faster encoding.</p><ul><li><strong>Multi-Vendor GPU Support:</strong> It auto-detects <strong>NVIDIA (NVENC)</strong>, <strong>Intel (QSV)</strong>, and <strong>AMD (VAAPI)</strong> hardware acceleration.</li><li><strong>Automatic CPU Fallback:</strong> If you don&apos;t have a compatible GPU, or if a driver is missing, it seamlessly falls back to CPU encoding (libx264, libx265, libaom-av1) so the job still gets done.</li><li><strong>Target-Size-First:</strong> The UI is built around <em>file size</em>, not confusing bitrate calculations. It does the math for you.</li><li><strong>Smart Auto-Retry:</strong> If the first pass misses the target (e.g., it comes out 2% over), it automatically runs a second pass with an adjusted bitrate to nail the file size.</li><li><strong>Modern UI:</strong> You get a live queue, real-time progress bars, and streaming FFmpeg logs directly in the browser thanks to Server-Sent Events (SSE). You can even run multiple jobs at once.</li></ul><p>It&apos;s the tool I always wanted: a &quot;set it and forget it&quot; service running in my lab that my whole family (or team) can use without needing to understand video codecs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-video-card kg-width-regular kg-card-hascaption" data-kg-thumbnail="https://noted.lol/content/media/2025/11/DEMO_thumb.jpg" data-kg-custom-thumbnail>
            <div class="kg-video-container">
                <video src="https://noted.lol/content/media/2025/11/DEMO.mp4" poster="https://img.spacergif.org/v1/3834x1898/0a/spacer.png" width="3834" height="1898" playsinline preload="metadata" style="background: transparent url(&apos;https://noted.lol/content/media/2025/11/DEMO_thumb.jpg&apos;) 50% 50% / cover no-repeat;"></video>
                <div class="kg-video-overlay">
                    <button class="kg-video-large-play-icon" aria-label="Play video">
                        <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 24 24">
                            <path d="M23.14 10.608 2.253.164A1.559 1.559 0 0 0 0 1.557v20.887a1.558 1.558 0 0 0 2.253 1.392L23.14 13.393a1.557 1.557 0 0 0 0-2.785Z"/>
                        </svg>
                    </button>
                </div>
                <div class="kg-video-player-container">
                    <div class="kg-video-player">
                        <button class="kg-video-play-icon" aria-label="Play video">
                            <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 24 24">
                                <path d="M23.14 10.608 2.253.164A1.559 1.559 0 0 0 0 1.557v20.887a1.558 1.558 0 0 0 2.253 1.392L23.14 13.393a1.557 1.557 0 0 0 0-2.785Z"/>
                            </svg>
                        </button>
                        <button class="kg-video-pause-icon kg-video-hide" aria-label="Pause video">
                            <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 24 24">
                                <rect x="3" y="1" width="7" height="22" rx="1.5" ry="1.5"/>
                                <rect x="14" y="1" width="7" height="22" rx="1.5" ry="1.5"/>
                            </svg>
                        </button>
                        <span class="kg-video-current-time">0:00</span>
                        <div class="kg-video-time">
                            /<span class="kg-video-duration">1:05</span>
                        </div>
                        <input type="range" class="kg-video-seek-slider" max="100" value="0">
                        <button class="kg-video-playback-rate" aria-label="Adjust playback speed">1&#xD7;</button>
                        <button class="kg-video-unmute-icon" aria-label="Unmute">
                            <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 24 24">
                                <path d="M15.189 2.021a9.728 9.728 0 0 0-7.924 4.85.249.249 0 0 1-.221.133H5.25a3 3 0 0 0-3 3v2a3 3 0 0 0 3 3h1.794a.249.249 0 0 1 .221.133 9.73 9.73 0 0 0 7.924 4.85h.06a1 1 0 0 0 1-1V3.02a1 1 0 0 0-1.06-.998Z"/>
                            </svg>
                        </button>
                        <button class="kg-video-mute-icon kg-video-hide" aria-label="Mute">
                            <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 24 24">
                                <path d="M16.177 4.3a.248.248 0 0 0 .073-.176v-1.1a1 1 0 0 0-1.061-1 9.728 9.728 0 0 0-7.924 4.85.249.249 0 0 1-.221.133H5.25a3 3 0 0 0-3 3v2a3 3 0 0 0 3 3h.114a.251.251 0 0 0 .177-.073ZM23.707 1.706A1 1 0 0 0 22.293.292l-22 22a1 1 0 0 0 0 1.414l.009.009a1 1 0 0 0 1.405-.009l6.63-6.631A.251.251 0 0 1 8.515 17a.245.245 0 0 1 .177.075 10.081 10.081 0 0 0 6.5 2.92 1 1 0 0 0 1.061-1V9.266a.247.247 0 0 1 .073-.176Z"/>
                            </svg>
                        </button>
                        <input type="range" class="kg-video-volume-slider" max="100" value="100">
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <figcaption><p><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Video Demo</span></p></figcaption>
        </figure><hr><h2 id="how-to-install-8mblocal-with-docker">How to Install 8mb.local with Docker</h2><p>Getting started is simple. The entire application stack (frontend, backend, worker, and Redis broker) is bundled into one Docker image.</p><p>You just need to choose the right <code>docker-compose.yml</code> for your hardware.</p><h3 id="1-cpu-only-works-everywhere">1. CPU-Only (Works Everywhere)</h3><p>This is the simplest setup and works on any machine (Windows, macOS, Linux).</p><p>YAML</p><pre><code>services:
  8mblocal:
    image: jms1717/8mblocal:latest
    container_name: 8mblocal
    ports:
      - &quot;8001:8001&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./uploads:/app/uploads
      - ./outputs:/app/outputs
    restart: unless-stopped
</code></pre><h3 id="2-nvidia-gpu-nvenc">2. NVIDIA GPU (NVENC)</h3><p>This is the one you want for maximum performance. It uses the <code>deploy</code> key to give the container access to your NVIDIA GPU.</p><p><strong>Critically</strong>, you must add the <code>NVIDIA_DRIVER_CAPABILITIES</code> environment variable. This tells the NVIDIA Container Toolkit to mount the <em>video encoding</em> libraries, not just the compute libraries.</p><p>YAML</p><pre><code>services:
  8mblocal:
    image: jms1717/8mblocal:latest
    container_name: 8mblocal
    ports:
      - &quot;8001:8001&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./uploads:/app/uploads
      - ./outputs:/app/outputs
    restart: unless-stopped
    environment:
      # REQUIRED for NVENC
      - NVIDIA_DRIVER_CAPABILITIES=compute,video,utility  
    deploy:
      resources:
        reservations:
          devices:
            - driver: nvidia
              count: all
              capabilities: [gpu]
</code></pre><h3 id="3-intelamd-gpu-vaapilinux-only">3. Intel/AMD GPU (VAAPI - Linux Only)</h3><p>If you&apos;re running on a Linux host with an Intel iGPU (QSV) or an AMD GPU (VAAPI), you can get hardware acceleration by passing through the <code>/dev/dri</code> device.</p><p>YAML</p><pre><code>services:
  8mblocal:
    image: jms1717/8mblocal:latest
    container_name: 8mblocal
    ports:
      - &quot;8001:8001&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./uploads:/app/uploads
      - ./outputs:/app/outputs
    devices:
      - /dev/dri:/dev/dri # Pass through the GPU
    restart: unless-stopped
</code></pre><hr><h2 id="%E2%9A%A0%EF%B8%8F-a-common-pitfall-and-how-to-fix-it">&#x26A0;&#xFE0F; A Common Pitfall (and How to Fix It)</h2><p>I&#x2019;ve spent time in the troubleshooting trenches so you don&apos;t have to. Here is one of the most common issues self-hosters run into.</p><h3 id="my-progress-bar-is-stuck-at-0-until-its-done">&quot;My progress bar is stuck at 0% until it&apos;s done!&quot;</h3><p></p><p>This is almost always a <strong>reverse proxy buffering</strong> problem.</p><p><code>8mb.local</code> uses Server-Sent Events (SSE) to stream real-time progress. If you put it behind Nginx, Nginx Proxy Manager, or Traefik, the proxy might buffer the entire response instead of streaming it.</p><p><strong>The Fix:</strong> You need to disable buffering for the SSE endpoint.</p><p>For <strong>Nginx / Nginx Proxy Manager</strong>, add this to your advanced configuration:</p><p>Nginx</p><pre><code>location /api/stream/ {
    proxy_pass http://YOUR_8MBLOCAL_IP:8001;
    proxy_buffering off;              # REQUIRED
    proxy_cache off;
    proxy_set_header Connection &apos;&apos;;
    chunked_transfer_encoding on;
}
</code></pre><p>This ensures you get that smooth, real-time feedback.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/queue.png" class="kg-image" alt="The 10MB Discord Limit Drove Me to Build a Self-Hosted GPU Video Compressor" loading="lazy" width="1780" height="846" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/queue.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/queue.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/11/queue.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/queue.png 1780w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Example of what it should look like</span></figcaption></figure><hr><h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2><p></p><p>As I mentioned, this is my first real open-source side project. I built it to solve a personal frustration, but I&apos;m thrilled to contribute something back to the self-hosting and homelab community that I&apos;ve learned so much from.</p><p>It&#x2019;s been a fantastic learning experience, and I&apos;m excited to see if other people find it as useful as I do.</p><p>Stop fighting with HandBrake presets. Give <code>8mb.local</code> a try, check out the <a href="https://github.com/JMS1717/8mb.local?ref=noted.lol" rel="noopener">project on GitHub</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn a hands on n8n homelab project that automates media conversion, frees up space with smart compression and cleanup, and gives you a fun rainy day tinkering task.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/self-running-video-encoder-bash-n8n/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">690b6a2268607e00017c1893</guid><category><![CDATA[n8n]]></category><category><![CDATA[How To]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:17:51 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-media-conversion.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-media-conversion.jpg" alt="The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion"><p>There are already great tools out there like FileFlows, Tdarr, and even Emby that can handle conversions for you. But half the fun of a homelab is building something yourself. If you&#x2019;ve been curious about n8n and want a small, hands-on project for a quiet afternoon, this is a good place to start.</p><p>This setup finds non-MP4 video files, converts them to MP4, logs detailed results for each one, and sends a report into n8n for storage or automation. It uses one bash script and one small workflow, but the design makes it easy to expand or maintain.</p><hr><h2 id="1-configuration-and-environment-setup">1. Configuration and environment setup</h2><p>At the top of the script, we define the default paths and key variables that control how everything runs:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">DEFAULT_WATCH=&quot;/mnt/media/Example&quot;
TMP_DIR=&quot;/mnt/storage/utilities/tmp_convert&quot;
LOG_DIR=&quot;/mnt/storage/utilities/logs&quot;
RESULTS_FILE=&quot;/tmp/encode_results_$$.json&quot;
LOCK_FILE=&quot;/tmp/encode_results.lock&quot;
NTFY_URL=&quot;https://ntfy.example.com/video-encode&quot;</code></pre><p>These tell the script where to find videos, where to write temporary conversions, where to save logs, and how to send notifications. The results file includes the process ID so that every run is unique and cannot overlap.</p><p>After defining them, the script creates the required folders and clears any leftover temporary files older than thirty minutes:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">mkdir -p &quot;$TMP_DIR&quot; &quot;$LOG_DIR&quot;
echo &quot;[]&quot; &gt; &quot;$RESULTS_FILE&quot;
find &quot;$TMP_DIR&quot; -type f -name &quot;*_tmp_*.mp4&quot; -mmin +30 -delete 2&gt;/dev/null || true</code></pre><p>This ensures the environment is clean before each run begins.</p><hr><h2 id="2-command-line-controls">2. Command-line controls</h2><p>The script accepts two flags to change its behavior.</p><p>The <code>-d</code> flag runs it in dry mode so it will simulate conversions without replacing files. The <code>-p</code> flag changes how many files can process at once. For example, <code>-p 6</code> means six encodes will run in parallel.</p><p>This logic is handled with a short argument parser:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">while getopts &quot;:dp:&quot; opt; do
  case $opt in
    d) DRY_RUN=1 ;;
    p) PARALLEL=&quot;$OPTARG&quot; ;;
    \?) echo &quot;Invalid option: -$OPTARG&quot; &gt;&amp;2; exit 2 ;;
    :) echo &quot;Option -$OPTARG requires an argument.&quot; &gt;&amp;2; exit 2 ;;
  esac
done</code></pre><p>If you provide a folder after the flags, the script uses that folder instead of the default watch path.</p><hr><h2 id="3-startup-notification-and-file-discovery">3. Startup notification and file discovery</h2><p>Once setup is complete, the script sends a notification that the process has started. It uses curl to post a simple message to ntfy with the hostname and folder being scanned:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">curl -s -H &quot;Title: &#x1F3AC; Encoding Started&quot; -H &quot;Priority: 3&quot; \
  -d &quot;Scanning for files in: $WATCH_DIR on homelab-server&quot; &quot;$NTFY_URL&quot;</code></pre><p>Then it searches for all files that are not already MP4:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">mapfile -d &apos;&apos; FILES &lt; &lt;(find &quot;$WATCH_DIR&quot; -type f \( -iname &quot;*.mkv&quot; -o -iname &quot;*.mov&quot; -o -iname &quot;*.avi&quot; -o -iname &quot;*.flv&quot; -o -iname &quot;*.ts&quot; \) -print0)</code></pre><p>If none are found, it prints a small JSON object that says no files were detected, sends a &#x201C;no files found&#x201D; notification, and exits gracefully.</p><hr><h2 id="4-the-worker-function">4. The worker function</h2><p>The main work happens inside a function called <code>worker</code>. Each file passes through it independently, and multiple workers can run at the same time.</p><pre><code class="language-bash">worker() {
  FILE=&quot;$1&quot;
  BASENAME=$(basename &quot;$FILE&quot;)</code></pre><p>The worker sets up a unique temporary file path and a timestamped log file:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">RAND_SUFFIX=$(tr -dc &apos;A-Za-z0-9&apos; &lt;/dev/urandom | head -c 5)
TMP=&quot;$TMP_DIR/${BASENAME%.*}_tmp_${RAND_SUFFIX}.mp4&quot;
TS=$(date +&quot;%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S&quot;)
LOG=&quot;$LOG_DIR/${BASENAME%.*}_${TS}.log&quot;
OUT=&quot;${FILE%.*}.mp4&quot;</code></pre><p>It validates that the source has a duration and size greater than zero using ffprobe and stat. If either test fails, it writes a small JSON object to the results file and skips the file.</p><p>Then it calculates a target bitrate that is half of the original, but never lower than 200 kilobits per second:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">ORIG_BPS=$(( SIZE_BYTES * 8 / DURATION_INT ))
TARGET_KBPS=$(( ORIG_BPS * 50 / 100 / 1000 ))
[ &quot;$TARGET_KBPS&quot; -lt 200 ] &amp;&amp; TARGET_KBPS=200</code></pre><p>The encoder is chosen based on GPU availability.<br>If an NVIDIA GPU is detected, the script uses <code>hevc_nvenc</code>.<br>Otherwise it uses <code>libx265</code> with a medium preset.</p><p>Subtitles are also handled here. The script checks for an English subtitle track and, if it is text based, converts it to mov_text for MP4 compatibility. Image subtitles are skipped and recorded in the log.</p><p>Finally, ffmpeg runs the conversion:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">ffmpeg -hide_banner -y -nostats -i &quot;$FILE&quot; \
  &quot;${MAP_OPTS[@]}&quot; \
  &quot;${VIDEO_OPTS[@]}&quot; -c:a aac -b:a 128k &quot;${SUB_OPTS[@]}&quot; \
  -movflags +faststart &quot;$TMP&quot; 2&gt; &quot;$LOG&quot;</code></pre><p>If ffmpeg fails or the temporary file does not appear, the worker marks the file as failed.</p><p>The new file replaces the old one atomically and the space saved is recorded in megabytes. All writes to the shared results file use flock and jq to ensure multiple workers never overwrite each other.</p><hr><h2 id="5-running-workers-in-parallel">5. Running workers in parallel</h2><p>After the worker function is defined, the script feeds every file path into it through xargs. The number of simultaneous workers depends on the parallel variable:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">printf &apos;%s\0&apos; &quot;${FILES[@]}&quot; | xargs -0 -n 1 -P &quot;$PARALLEL&quot; bash -c &apos;worker &quot;$1&quot;&apos; _</code></pre><p>This line runs each file through the worker and waits for all to complete before continuing.</p><hr><h2 id="6-building-the-summary-report">6. Building the summary report</h2><p>Once all workers are finished, the script collects totals from the results file using jq. It counts how many succeeded, failed, skipped, or were part of a dry run, and sums the total space saved:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">TOTAL_SAVED=$(jq &apos;[.[] | select(.status==&quot;success&quot; or .status==&quot;dryrun&quot;) | .saved_mb] | add // 0&apos; &quot;$RESULTS_FILE&quot;)
SUCCESS_COUNT=$(jq &apos;[.[] | select(.status==&quot;success&quot;)] | length&apos; &quot;$RESULTS_FILE&quot;)</code></pre><p>The data is then formatted into a single JSON summary that includes the folder name, totals, and per-file details. That summary is printed to standard output or stdout so n8n can capture it.</p><hr><h2 id="7-completion-notification-and-cleanup">7. Completion notification and cleanup</h2><p>After printing the summary, the script sends a completion message through ntfy that shows how many files succeeded, failed, or were skipped, along with the total space saved.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/ntfy-encode-complete.PNG" class="kg-image" alt="The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion" loading="lazy" width="1284" height="565" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/ntfy-encode-complete.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/ntfy-encode-complete.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/ntfy-encode-complete.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Finally, it cleans up any temporary files left behind:</p><pre><code class="language-bash">find &quot;$TMP_DIR&quot; -type f -delete 2&gt;/dev/null || true</code></pre><p>At this point, every log and result is stored, and the environment is ready for the next scheduled run.</p><p>You can download and see the entire bash script here:</p><div class="kg-card kg-file-card"><a class="kg-file-card-container" href="https://noted.lol/content/files/2025/11/encode-ntfy-n8n.sh" title="Download" download><div class="kg-file-card-contents"><div class="kg-file-card-title">encode-ntfy-n8n</div><div class="kg-file-card-caption"></div><div class="kg-file-card-metadata"><div class="kg-file-card-filename">encode-ntfy-n8n.sh</div><div class="kg-file-card-filesize">7 KB</div></div></div><div class="kg-file-card-icon"><svg viewbox="0 0 24 24"><defs><style>.a{fill:none;stroke:currentColor;stroke-linecap:round;stroke-linejoin:round;stroke-width:1.5px;}</style></defs><title>download-circle</title><polyline class="a" points="8.25 14.25 12 18 15.75 14.25"/><line class="a" x1="12" y1="6.75" x2="12" y2="18"/><circle class="a" cx="12" cy="12" r="11.25"/></svg></div></a></div><hr><h2 id="8-integrating-the-script-with-n8n">8. Integrating the script with n8n</h2><p>The script is written to work directly with n8n using the Execute Command node.<br>A simple workflow can automate it completely.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-encode-media-ntfy-workflow.png" class="kg-image" alt="The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion" loading="lazy" width="1044" height="349" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/n8n-encode-media-ntfy-workflow.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/n8n-encode-media-ntfy-workflow.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-encode-media-ntfy-workflow.png 1044w"></figure><p><strong>Step one</strong> uses a Schedule Trigger to start the job on a regular interval.<br><strong>Step two</strong> runs the bash script and captures its JSON output.<br><strong>Step three</strong> uses a Code node to parse the summary, format readable messages, and extract important values such as total files converted and total space saved.<br><strong>Step four</strong> stores each run in a Data Table for history and dashboards.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-encode-data-table.png" class="kg-image" alt="The Complex Beauty of Bash and n8n in Media Conversion" loading="lazy" width="1416" height="664" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/11/n8n-encode-data-table.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/11/n8n-encode-data-table.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/11/n8n-encode-data-table.png 1416w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><p>Because the script already outputs structured JSON, n8n can read it without extra parsing. You can also connect an HTTP Request node to forward notifications to Discord or another ntfy topic.</p><p>You can download and see the entire n8n workflow json here to import.</p><div class="kg-card kg-file-card"><a class="kg-file-card-container" href="https://noted.lol/content/files/2025/11/n8n-encode-workflow.json" title="Download" download><div class="kg-file-card-contents"><div class="kg-file-card-title">n8n-encode-workflow</div><div class="kg-file-card-caption"></div><div class="kg-file-card-metadata"><div class="kg-file-card-filename">n8n-encode-workflow.json</div><div class="kg-file-card-filesize">4 KB</div></div></div><div class="kg-file-card-icon"><svg viewbox="0 0 24 24"><defs><style>.a{fill:none;stroke:currentColor;stroke-linecap:round;stroke-linejoin:round;stroke-width:1.5px;}</style></defs><title>download-circle</title><polyline class="a" points="8.25 14.25 12 18 15.75 14.25"/><line class="a" x1="12" y1="6.75" x2="12" y2="18"/><circle class="a" cx="12" cy="12" r="11.25"/></svg></div></a></div><hr><h2 id="9-why-this-design-works-but-isnt-practical">9. Why this design works but isn&apos;t practical</h2><p>The script handles all the encoding and file management while n8n takes care of scheduling, transformation, and storage. Each part does its own job, which keeps the whole setup simple to understand and easy to maintain.</p><p>You can change encoder settings, add new notifications, or expand the summary with more information without touching the rest of the workflow. Everything stays modular and predictable. The result is a complete, self-contained system that keeps your media library consistent and organized.</p><p>That was fun, but expect to tweak the script from time to time. Certain files will probably need manual handling or code changes. You can check your logs folder for failures or even modify the script to let you know what fails and where.</p><h2 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h2><p>Is this completely unnecessary? Probably. But it was a fun build that taught me more than I expected. I learned how flexible ffmpeg really is, how much control you can get from a few lines in the terminal, and how easily n8n can turn a local script into a repeatable automation.</p><p>There are plenty of tools that already do this, but this project was a learning experience more than anything. Seeing the workflow run, report, clean up and send notifications on its own is satisfying in a way that clicking a preset button never is. It reminded me why homelabs exist in the first place. To experiment, break things, fix them, and enjoy the process of making something work exactly how you want it to. Will it replace FileFlows for me? I&apos;m optimistic but we will see!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync]]></title><description><![CDATA[Automate seamless file backups from your server to a Synology NAS using n8n, rsync, and Samba. This workflow keeps your data mirrored, sends instant notifications, and gives you a clear view of your storage every time it runs.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/n8n-fle-sync-with-rsync/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69036c8768607e00017c0cfa</guid><category><![CDATA[n8n]]></category><category><![CDATA[Homelab]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:52:48 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-file-sync-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-file-sync-noted.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync"><p>Most of us copy files by hand or run the same rsync command every few days, hoping we did not miss anything. With n8n and rsync, you can make that entire process automatic.</p><p>Before setting up the workflow, I created a shared folder on my Synology NAS and connected it to my server using Samba. The share was mounted under <code>/mnt/synomediabackup</code>, which allowed the server to treat it like a local directory. Once that connection was working, n8n could run rsync directly between the two paths without any extra network steps.</p><p>This small piece is important. Without Samba, rsync would need to connect over SSH or another remote method. By mounting the NAS share first, everything stays local and fast, and permissions are handled cleanly by the system.</p><p>With that in place, n8n takes care of the rest. It runs the sync, cleans up old files, checks free space, and sends a message when it is done. Three nodes, one routine solved forever.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-workflow-server-nas-sync.png" class="kg-image" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" loading="lazy" width="1430" height="636" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/n8n-workflow-server-nas-sync.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/n8n-workflow-server-nas-sync.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-workflow-server-nas-sync.png 1430w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><hr><h3 id="workflow-summary">Workflow Summary</h3>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<table data-start="1447" data-end="1698" class="w-fit min-w-(--thread-content-width)"><thead data-start="1447" data-end="1472"><tr data-start="1447" data-end="1472"><th data-start="1447" data-end="1454" data-col-size="sm">Node</th><th data-start="1454" data-end="1461" data-col-size="sm">Type</th><th data-start="1461" data-end="1472" data-col-size="md">Purpose</th></tr></thead><tbody data-start="1500" data-end="1698"><tr data-start="1500" data-end="1575"><td data-start="1500" data-end="1504" data-col-size="sm">1</td><td data-col-size="sm" data-start="1504" data-end="1522">Execute Command</td><td data-col-size="md" data-start="1522" data-end="1575">Runs the rsync job and reports storage after sync</td></tr><tr data-start="1576" data-end="1641"><td data-start="1576" data-end="1580" data-col-size="sm">2</td><td data-col-size="sm" data-start="1580" data-end="1587">Code</td><td data-col-size="md" data-start="1587" data-end="1641">Parses the rsync output and builds a short summary</td></tr><tr data-start="1642" data-end="1698"><td data-start="1642" data-end="1646" data-col-size="sm">3</td><td data-start="1646" data-end="1661" data-col-size="sm">HTTP Request</td><td data-col-size="md" data-start="1661" data-end="1698">Sends a notification through ntfy</td></tr></tbody></table>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<ol><li>Execute Command Node</li></ol><p>The first node runs rsync from your main media folder to the NAS and checks how much storage is left when it finishes.</p><pre><code class="language-bash">rsync -a --delete --stats \
--exclude=$RECYCLE.BIN \
--exclude=.sync \
--exclude=aquota.group \
--exclude=aquota.user \
/mnt/media/TV/TV/ /mnt/synomediabackup/TV/ ; \
echo &quot; &quot;; \
echo &quot;---- Storage After Sync ----&quot; ; \
df -h /mnt/synomediabackup
</code></pre><p>This keeps your NAS perfectly mirrored. The delete flag removes files that no longer exist on your server so you always have an exact copy. The exclude lines skip folders that do not need to be backed up. The final <code>df -h</code> command shows how much free space remains after the sync completes.</p><ol start="2"><li>Code Node</li></ol><p>The second node cleans up the rsync output and turns it into a short, clear message.</p><pre><code class="language-json">const output = $json.stdout || &quot;&quot;;

// Extract created (new) files
const createdMatch = output.match(/Number of created files:\s+(\d+)/);
const added = createdMatch ? parseInt(createdMatch[1]) : 0;

// Extract deleted files
const deletedMatch = output.match(/Number of deleted files:\s+(\d+)/);
const deleted = deletedMatch ? parseInt(deletedMatch[1]) : 0;

// Extract transferred file size (bytes)
const sentBytesMatch = output.match(/Total transferred file size:\s+([\d,]+)/);
let sentGB = &quot;0 GB&quot;;

if (sentBytesMatch) {
  const bytes = parseInt(sentBytesMatch[1].replace(/,/g, &quot;&quot;));
  const gb = bytes / (1024 ** 3);
  sentGB = gb.toFixed(2) + &quot; GB&quot;;
}

// Extract free space (use Avail column from df -h)
const freeMatch = output.match(/\s+(\d+(\.\d+)?[GT])\s+\d+%/i);
const free = freeMatch ? freeMatch[1].toUpperCase() : &quot;Unknown&quot;;

// Build one-line summary
const summary = `&#x2705; TV Sync &#x2022; Added: ${added} &#x2022; Deleted: ${deleted} &#x2022; Sent: ${sentGB} &#x2022; Free: ${free}`;

return [{ summary }];</code></pre><ol start="3"><li>HTTP Request Node</li></ol><p>After the workflow runs, you get a clean report that looks something like this:</p><blockquote>&#x2705; TV Sync &#x2022; Added: 12 &#x2022; Deleted: 3 &#x2022; Sent: 5.42 GB &#x2022; Free: 3.7T</blockquote><p>This will be parsed out to ntfy to send a push notification to my iPhone.</p><p>The final node sends that summary to <strong>ntfy</strong> so you get a message the moment the sync finishes.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/ntfy-sync-stats.PNG" class="kg-image" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" loading="lazy" width="1284" height="642" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/ntfy-sync-stats.PNG 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/ntfy-sync-stats.PNG 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/ntfy-sync-stats.PNG 1284w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Here you can see the push notification that came through on my iPhone. It shows that 29 files were added, 23 were deleted, and about 50.49 gigabytes were transferred, leaving 7.1 terabytes of free space on the NAS. It is a quick snapshot that tells me everything I need to know without ever opening the NAS dashboard.<br><br>You might notice that some files are being deleted during the sync. That happens because I run a file converter on the server, so whenever a file is changed, the old version on the NAS gets replaced. The rsync command keeps the NAS as a perfect mirror of the server&#x2019;s file structure.</p><p>You can subscribe to that topic on your phone or browser. I go over how to setup ntfy in n8n in more detail here:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/hdd-health-alerts-using-n8n-and-ntfy/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Self-Hosted HDD Health Alerts using n8n and ntfy</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Monitor your drives with n8n and SmartMonTools and get instant notifications with ntfy for real-time health and temperature updates.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-30.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-ntfy-noted.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><p>Or learn more about Ntfy here:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/ntfy/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Self-Hosted Push Notifications with Ntfy on iOS</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Learn how to set up ntfy, a self-hosted push notification service, on iOS with a simple workaround. Explore how ntfy makes notifications easy, reliable, and fully open source.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-37.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/ntfy-self-hosted-push-notifications-noted.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>This setup is small but powerful. The Samba share keeps everything local and simple, rsync handles the transfer with precision, and n8n ties it all together with automation and feedback.</p><p>I could have handled this with a plain cron job and been done with it, but using n8n gives me something better. I can actually see what is happening, track each step, and build on it with extras like notifications or even log the information into a data table like this.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-sync-table.png" class="kg-image" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="392" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/n8n-sync-table.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/n8n-sync-table.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/n8n-sync-table.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-sync-table.png 1920w"></figure><p>Yup, you can do that too. n8n now has built in tables so you don&apos;t have to connect to Google sheets anymore!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/tag/n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">n8n - Noted</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">I&#x2019;m obsessed with n8n so I made it a category. Here&#x2019;s all things related to n8n.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-31.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8-systemlog-workflow.png" alt="Automate File Syncs from Your Server to Synology with n8n and rsync" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to use Komodo’s Deployments page to run Docker containers from a clean, browser-based interface.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/komodo-deplyments/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f6479568607e00017bf6c2</guid><category><![CDATA[How To]]></category><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Web Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:52:25 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/kmodo-deployments-main-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/kmodo-deployments-main-noted.png" alt="Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface"><p>Komodo gives you a clean, browser-based way to manage your Docker environment. It turns the usual terminal commands into a visual workflow that makes sense at a glance. For developers, hobbyists, or homelab users, it&#x2019;s a simpler and faster way to handle container deployments without giving up the control Docker provides.</p><p>In this article, we&#x2019;ll look at how to use Komodo&#x2019;s <strong>Deployments</strong> page to run Docker containers directly from the web interface.</p><hr><h3 id="what-is-komodo">What is Komodo</h3><p><a href="https://noted.lol/komodo/">Komodo</a> is a self-hosted Docker management tool that lets you interact with your containers, images, and networks through a web dashboard. It&#x2019;s designed to feel modern and responsive while staying close to Docker&#x2019;s core structure.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/komodo/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">Komodo - Manage Docker Images &amp; Containers Across Multiple Servers</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">Managing servers, containers, and deployments can quickly get messy when you&#x2019;re juggling multiple tools. That&#x2019;s where Komodo comes in. It brings everything under one roof. Monitoring, automation, and deployments. What is Komodo? Komodo is a web app built to simplify server and deployment management. It connects all your</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-28.png" alt="Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/komodo-self-hosted-noted.png" alt="Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><p>Under the hood, it still uses the same <code>docker run</code> commands you&#x2019;d type manually. The difference is that Komodo&#x2019;s interface helps you visualize those commands, organize them, and reuse them more easily.</p><p>You can define container settings, build Compose stacks, and even manage multiple hosts using Periphery agents, all from one place.</p><hr><h3 id="why-use-komodo-for-docker-deployments">Why Use Komodo for Docker Deployments</h3><p>Using the Deployments page brings structure to how you launch containers. Instead of pasting random commands from documentation or notes, you build and save deployments that can be reused, modified, or redeployed later.</p><p>Some of the best parts include:</p><ul><li>A visual form for <code>docker run</code> configuration</li><li>Built-in environment variable and volume mapping support</li><li>Persistent deployment templates for future use</li><li>One-click redeploys when you update an image or tweak a setting</li></ul><h3 id="using-the-deployments-page">Using the Deployments Page</h3><p>Open <strong>Deployments</strong> in the Komodo sidebar, then click N<strong>ew Deployment</strong>.</p><p>You&#x2019;ll be guided through a series of fields that represent the same options you&#x2019;d use in a <code>docker run</code> command:</p><ul><li><strong>Image name:</strong> Choose the image you want to run</li><li><strong>Network:</strong>  Default to bridge if you don&apos;t know what you&apos;re doing (and to allow port changes)</li><li><strong>Ports:</strong> Map container ports to host ports</li><li><strong>Volumes:</strong> Mount directories or data volumes</li><li><strong>Environment variables:</strong> Set custom values for your app</li><li><strong>Restart Mode:</strong> Fine-tune how the container behaves</li></ul><p>As you fill out each field, Komodo builds a valid <code>docker run</code> command in real time. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/komodo-self-hosted-docker-management-docker-run.png" class="kg-image" alt="Using Komodo to Run Docker Commands from a Web Interface" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="909" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/komodo-self-hosted-docker-management-docker-run.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/komodo-self-hosted-docker-management-docker-run.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/komodo-self-hosted-docker-management-docker-run.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/komodo-self-hosted-docker-management-docker-run.png 1920w"></figure><p>Once you hit <strong>Deploy</strong>, Komodo creates the container and tracks it automatically. The new container appears in your Containers list, complete with logs, resource stats, and quick actions for restarting or removing it.</p><hr><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>The Deployments page makes Komodo feel like a natural extension of Docker itself. You&#x2019;re still in control of what happens&#x2014;you just don&#x2019;t have to memorize every flag or dig through your command history.</p><p>For anyone managing multiple containers, Komodo&#x2019;s Deployments system turns Docker management into something clear, visual, and repeatable. It&#x2019;s one of those rare tools that makes your workflow easier without hiding what&#x2019;s going on under the hood.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Backing Up GitHub Repositories the Easy Way with Gitea Mirror]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gitea Mirror automatically syncs your GitHub repositories to your self-hosted Gitea instance. Open source, easy to deploy, and built for developers who want peace of mind.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/gitea-mirror/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f8c73668607e00017bfda5</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Web Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:32:05 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/gitea-mirror-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/gitea-mirror-noted.png" alt="Backing Up GitHub Repositories the Easy Way with Gitea Mirror"><p>Most of us never think much about where our code actually lives. We push to GitHub, close the laptop, and move on. It only takes one bad moment to realize how much we rely on it. A deleted repo, a locked account, or an outage can change everything. I wanted a simple way to keep a second copy of everything I write, and that is how I found Gitea Mirror.</p><h3 id="what-is-gitea-mirror">What is Gitea Mirror?</h3><p><a href="https://giteamirror.com/?ref=noted.lol">Gitea Mirror</a> is a self-hosted tool that keeps your GitHub repositories backed up and in sync with your own Gitea instance. It&#x2019;s open source, simple to run, and made for developers who like having their own copy of everything they build.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/gitea-mirror-backups-dashboard-1.webp" width="2000" height="1228" loading="lazy" alt="Backing Up GitHub Repositories the Easy Way with Gitea Mirror" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-backups-dashboard-1.webp 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/gitea-mirror-backups-dashboard-1.webp 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-backups-dashboard-1.webp 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/10/gitea-mirror-backups-dashboard-1.webp 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/gitea-mirror-organisation.webp" width="2000" height="1220" loading="lazy" alt="Backing Up GitHub Repositories the Easy Way with Gitea Mirror" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-organisation.webp 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/gitea-mirror-organisation.webp 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-organisation.webp 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/10/gitea-mirror-organisation.webp 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div></div></div></figure><h3 id="gitea-mirror-core-features">Gitea Mirror Core Features</h3><p><strong>Automatic Sync</strong><br>Gitea Mirror connects to your GitHub account and mirrors your repositories on a schedule you choose. Once configured, it quietly keeps your Gitea instance up to date without any manual steps.</p><p><strong>Private Repository Support</strong><br>With a GitHub token that includes the right permissions, you can mirror private repositories just as easily as public ones.</p><p><strong>Bulk Mirroring and Filtering</strong><br>You can mirror every repository from a user or organization, or filter which ones to include or skip. There&#x2019;s even support for mirroring the repositories you&#x2019;ve starred on GitHub.</p><p><strong>Preserve Organization Structure</strong><br>When copying repositories, Gitea Mirror can keep your GitHub organization and project structure intact so everything stays in familiar places.</p><p><strong>Dashboard and Logs</strong><br>The dashboard shows which repositories have synced, when they were last updated, and whether any failed. It&#x2019;s easy to check if everything is running as expected.</p><p><strong>Dry Run Option</strong><br>You can run it once in dry mode to test your setup before mirroring anything. It logs what would happen without making real changes.</p><p><strong>Open Source and Self-Hosted</strong><br>Gitea Mirror is open source under GPL-3.0, and because you host it yourself, you stay in full control of your data and environment.</p><h3 id="gitea-mirror-configuration-highlights">Gitea Mirror Configuration Highlights</h3><p>The <a href="https://github.com/RayLabsHQ/gitea-mirror/tree/main/docs?ref=noted.lol">Gitea Mirror docs</a> explain several useful options you can set through environment variables:</p><ul><li><strong><code>GITHUB_TOKEN</code></strong> &#x2013; required for access to your repositories, including private ones.</li><li><strong><code>GITEA_URL</code></strong> &#x2013; where to mirror your repositories.</li><li><strong><code>SYNC_INTERVAL</code></strong> &#x2013; how often mirrors run (for example, every few hours or daily).</li><li><strong><code>MIRROR_TYPE</code></strong> &#x2013; choose between user, organization, or starred repositories.</li><li><strong><code>PRESERVE_STRUCTURE</code></strong> &#x2013; keeps your organization and repo layout consistent.</li><li><strong><code>DRY_RUN</code></strong> &#x2013; preview changes before syncing for the first time.</li></ul><p>These small options make Gitea Mirror flexible enough for both simple personal setups and larger teams.</p><h3 id="how-gitea-mirror-works">How Gitea Mirror Works</h3><p>Setting up Gitea Mirror takes only a few steps. You pull the repository, tweak a couple of settings, and bring it up with <a href="https://github.com/RayLabsHQ/gitea-mirror?tab=readme-ov-file&amp;ref=noted.lol#-quick-start">Docker Compose</a>. After that, you connect your GitHub token, add your Gitea URL, choose how often it should sync, and you&#x2019;re done. It also has a <a href="https://github.com/RayLabsHQ/gitea-mirror?tab=readme-ov-file&amp;ref=noted.lol#lxc-container-proxmox">one line installer for Proxmox LXC</a>!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/gitea-mirror-configuration.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Backing Up GitHub Repositories the Easy Way with Gitea Mirror" loading="lazy" width="2000" height="1220" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-configuration.webp 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/gitea-mirror-configuration.webp 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/gitea-mirror-configuration.webp 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/10/gitea-mirror-configuration.webp 2400w"></figure><p>It runs well on a small home server and handles bigger setups without trouble. Gitea Mirror doesn&#x2019;t try to replace anything. It just keeps your GitHub and Gitea in sync so your code is always backed up and easy to reach.</p><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>What I like about Gitea Mirror is that it just takes one more worry off the list. Once it&#x2019;s set up, you know your code is backed up and safe no matter what happens with GitHub. There&#x2019;s something reassuring about knowing every project you&#x2019;ve built lives on your own server, not someone else&#x2019;s.</p><p>If you end up trying it out, stop by the <a href="https://github.com/RayLabsHQ/gitea-mirror?ref=noted.lol">Gitea Mirror GitHub</a> page and give the project a star. It&#x2019;s a small way to support the developer for building something this useful.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a clean system log dashboard and smart SSH alert workflow using n8n. This guide walks through real log parsing, visual dashboards, and notifications when login attempts fail.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/system-log-dashboard-n8n/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f7834d68607e00017bf9db</guid><category><![CDATA[How To]]></category><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Monitoring Tools]]></category><category><![CDATA[n8n]]></category><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Automation Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:06:53 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-system-logs-dashboard-workflow-noted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-system-logs-dashboard-workflow-noted.png" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n"><p>This project started as a way for me to bring more visibility to what&#x2019;s happening on my Ubuntu server without needing to dig through logs manually. Using n8n, I built a workflow that reads system logs, parses out key details, and turns them into a clean HTML dashboard I can download or preview. Along the way, I added live counts, colors, and alerts for failed SSH login attempts.</p><p>The best part? It&#x2019;s all simple, script-driven, and easy to maintain.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-gallery-card kg-width-wide"><div class="kg-gallery-container"><div class="kg-gallery-row"><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-system-log-dashboard-noted-1.png" width="1920" height="916" loading="lazy" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/n8n-system-log-dashboard-noted-1.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/n8n-system-log-dashboard-noted-1.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/n8n-system-log-dashboard-noted-1.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8n-system-log-dashboard-noted-1.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div><div class="kg-gallery-image"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8-systemlog-workflow.png" width="1920" height="775" loading="lazy" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/n8-systemlog-workflow.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/n8-systemlog-workflow.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/n8-systemlog-workflow.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/n8-systemlog-workflow.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></div></div></div></figure><h3 id="building-the-workflow">Building the Workflow</h3><p>I began by pulling live data straight from the system using an <strong>Execute Command</strong> node. The command collected five core pieces of information:</p><ol><li><strong>System Errors and Warnings</strong> &#x2013; pulled from <code>journalctl</code> to catch anything marked error, fail, warn, or critical.</li><li><strong>Failed SSH Login Attempts</strong> &#x2013; parsed from <code>/var/log/auth.log</code> using <code>grep</code> and <code>awk</code> to count unique IPs.</li><li><strong>Successful SSH Logins</strong> &#x2013; showed recent accepted logins with usernames and IPs.</li><li><strong>Kernel Warnings</strong> &#x2013; extracted hardware and system-level messages with <code>dmesg</code>.</li><li><strong>Network Connection Attempts</strong> &#x2013; listed active connections using <code>ss -tuna</code>.</li></ol><p>All of this was wrapped in one compact command and piped into n8n as text output.</p><pre><code class="language-bash">( echo &quot;===== System Errors and Warnings =====&quot;; journalctl --system -p 4 -n 300 --no-pager --output=short-iso | grep -E &apos;error|fail|warn|critical&apos; || echo &apos;No system issues found&apos;; echo &quot;&quot;; echo &quot;===== Failed SSH Login Attempts =====&quot;; grep &quot;Failed password&quot; /var/log/auth.log | awk &apos;{print $(NF-3)}&apos; | sort | uniq -c | sort -nr | head -10 || echo &apos;No failed SSH attempts found&apos;; echo &quot;&quot;; echo &quot;===== Successful SSH Logins =====&quot;; grep &quot;Accepted&quot; /var/log/auth.log | tail -10 || echo &apos;No successful SSH logins found&apos;; echo &quot;&quot;; echo &quot;===== Kernel Warnings =====&quot;; dmesg | grep -iE &quot;error|warn|fail&quot; | tail -10 || echo &apos;No kernel warnings found&apos;; echo &quot;&quot;; echo &quot;===== Network Connection Attempts =====&quot;; ss -tuna | grep ESTAB | head -10 || echo &apos;No active network connections found&apos;; ) 2&gt;&amp;1</code></pre><p>Next came the <strong>Function node</strong>, which converted that plain-text data into a visual dashboard. The HTML layout included summary tiles at the top with live counts for each section, two-column organization, color-coded categories, and even a copy button for individual system errors.</p><pre><code class="language-html">const now = new Date().toLocaleString(&quot;en-US&quot;, { timeZone: &quot;America/Detroit&quot; });
const raw = $json.stdout || &quot;No logs found&quot;;

// --- Parse Sections ---
const cleaned = raw.replace(/\r/g, &quot;&quot;).replace(/\n{2,}/g, &quot;\n&quot;);
const regex = /={3,}\s*(.*?)\s*={3,}\n?([\s\S]*?)(?=(?:={3,}|$))/g;
const data = {};
let match;
while ((match = regex.exec(cleaned)) !== null) {
  const title = match[1].trim();
  const content = match[2].trim().split(&quot;\n&quot;).filter(l =&gt; l.trim());
  const filtered = content.filter(l =&gt; !/no .*found/i.test(l));
  data[title] = filtered.length &gt; 0 ? filtered : [];
}

// --- Render Section ---
function renderSection(title, lines, color) {
  const hasData = lines &amp;&amp; lines.length &gt; 0;

  // Network table
  if (title === &quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;) {
    if (!hasData)
      return `&lt;div class=&quot;section wide&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;${title}&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry empty&quot;&gt;No data found&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;`;
    const headers = [&quot;NetID&quot;, &quot;State&quot;, &quot;Recv-Q&quot;, &quot;Send-Q&quot;, &quot;Local Address:Port&quot;, &quot;Peer Address:Port&quot;];
    const rows = lines.map(line =&gt; {
      const cols = line.trim().split(/\s+/).slice(0, 6);
      return `&lt;tr&gt;${cols.map((c, i) =&gt; `&lt;td data-label=&quot;${headers[i] || &quot;&quot;}&quot;&gt;${c}&lt;/td&gt;`).join(&quot;&quot;)}&lt;/tr&gt;`;
    }).join(&quot;&quot;);
    return `
      &lt;div class=&quot;section wide&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;${title} (${lines.length})&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;table-wrapper&quot;&gt;
          &lt;table&gt;
            &lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;${headers.map(h =&gt; `&lt;th&gt;${h}&lt;/th&gt;`).join(&quot;&quot;)}&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
            &lt;tbody&gt;${rows}&lt;/tbody&gt;
          &lt;/table&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;`;
  }

  if (!hasData)
    return `&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;${title} (0)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry empty&quot;&gt;No data found&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;`;

  return `
    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;${title} (${lines.length})&lt;/h2&gt;
      ${lines.map((l, i) =&gt; {
        const safeText = l.replace(/&lt;/g, &quot;&amp;lt;&quot;);
        const id = `${title.replace(/\s+/g, &quot;_&quot;)}_${i}`;
        const copyBtn =
          title === &quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;
            ? `&lt;button class=&quot;copy-btn&quot; onclick=&quot;copyText(&apos;${id}&apos;)&quot;&gt;&#x29C9;&lt;/button&gt;`
            : &quot;&quot;;
        return `&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot; id=&quot;${id}&quot; style=&quot;border-left-color:${color}&quot;&gt;${safeText}${copyBtn}&lt;/div&gt;`;
      }).join(&quot;&quot;)}
    &lt;/div&gt;`;
}

// --- Colors ---
const colors = {
  &quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;: &quot;#ef4444&quot;,
  &quot;Failed SSH Login Attempts&quot;: &quot;#3b82f6&quot;,
  &quot;Successful SSH Logins&quot;: &quot;#22c55e&quot;,
  &quot;Kernel Warnings&quot;: &quot;#f59e0b&quot;,
  &quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;: &quot;#8b5cf6&quot;,
};

// --- Count Summary ---
const counts = {
  errors: data[&quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;]?.length || 0,
  failedSSH: data[&quot;Failed SSH Login Attempts&quot;]?.length || 0,
  successSSH: data[&quot;Successful SSH Logins&quot;]?.length || 0,
  kernel: data[&quot;Kernel Warnings&quot;]?.length || 0,
  network: data[&quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;]?.length || 0,
};

// --- HTML ---
let html = `
&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;&gt;
&lt;title&gt;System Log Dashboard&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css2?family=Inter:wght@400;500;600&amp;family=Poppins:wght@500;600&amp;display=swap&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  body {
    background: #0d0f13;
    color: #e5e7eb;
    font-family: &apos;Inter&apos;, sans-serif;
    padding: 1.5rem;
  }
  h1 {
    font-family: &apos;Poppins&apos;, sans-serif;
    font-weight: 600;
    font-size: 1.7rem;
    margin-bottom: 1rem;
    color: #fff;
  }
  p {
    color: #9ca3af;
    margin-bottom: 1.5rem;
  }
  .summary {
    display: flex;
    gap: 1rem;
    flex-wrap: wrap;
    margin-bottom: 1.5rem;
  }
  .card {
    flex: 1;
    min-width: 140px;
    background: rgba(255,255,255,0.04);
    border: 1px solid rgba(255,255,255,0.08);
    border-radius: 10px;
    padding: 1rem;
    text-align: center;
    box-shadow: 0 2px 6px rgba(0,0,0,0.3);
    transition: all 0.2s ease;
  }
  .card:hover {
    background: rgba(255,255,255,0.06);
  }
  .count {
    font-size: 1.4rem;
    font-weight: 600;
    margin-bottom: 0.3rem;
  }
  .label {
    font-size: 0.85rem;
    color: #9ca3af;
  }
  .errors .count { color: #ef4444; }
  .fails .count { color: #3b82f6; }
  .success .count { color: #22c55e; }
  .kernel .count { color: #f59e0b; }
  .network .count { color: #8b5cf6; }

  .grid {
    display: grid;
    grid-template-columns: repeat(2, 1fr);
    gap: 1rem;
  }
  .wide { grid-column: 1 / -1; }

  .section {
    background: rgba(255,255,255,0.04);
    border-radius: 8px;
    padding: 1rem;
    border: 1px solid rgba(255,255,255,0.07);
  }
  h2 {
    font-family: &apos;Poppins&apos;, sans-serif;
    font-size: 1rem;
    font-weight: 500;
    color: #cbd5e1;
    border-bottom: 1px solid rgba(255,255,255,0.05);
    margin: 0 0 0.6rem;
    padding-bottom: 0.3rem;
  }
  .entry {
    background: rgba(0,0,0,0.25);
    margin: 0.25rem 0;
    padding: 0.55rem 0.6rem;
    border-radius: 6px;
    font-size: 0.85rem;
    border-left: 3px solid;
    white-space: pre-wrap;
    position: relative;
  }
  .entry.empty {
    border-left-color: #4b5563;
    color: #9ca3af;
    font-style: italic;
  }
  .copy-btn {
    position: absolute;
    top: 6px;
    right: 8px;
    background: none;
    border: none;
    color: #60a5fa;
    cursor: pointer;
    font-size: 0.8rem;
    transition: 0.2s;
  }
  .copy-btn:hover { color: #93c5fd; }
  .table-wrapper { overflow-x: auto; margin-top: 0.4rem; }
  table {
    width: 100%;
    border-collapse: collapse;
    font-size: 0.85rem;
  }
  th, td {
    padding: 0.3rem 0.5rem;
    border-bottom: 1px solid rgba(255,255,255,0.05);
    text-align: left;
  }
  th {
    color: #cbd5e1;
    background: rgba(255,255,255,0.05);
    font-family: &apos;Poppins&apos;, sans-serif;
  }
  tr:hover td { background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0.03); }
  footer {
    color: #9ca3af;
    font-size: 0.75rem;
    text-align: center;
    margin-top: 1.5rem;
    border-top: 1px solid rgba(255,255,255,0.05);
    padding-top: 0.5rem;
  }
  @media (max-width: 900px) {
    .grid { grid-template-columns: 1fr; }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
function copyText(id) {
  const text = document.getElementById(id).innerText.replace(&apos;&#x29C9;&apos;,&apos;&apos;).trim();
  navigator.clipboard.writeText(text).then(() =&gt; {
    const btn = document.querySelector(&apos;#&apos; + id + &apos; .copy-btn&apos;);
    if (btn) {
      btn.textContent = &apos;&#x2714;&apos;;
      setTimeout(() =&gt; (btn.textContent = &apos;&#x29C9;&apos;), 1500);
    }
  });
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;System Log Dashboard&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generated: ${now}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card errors&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;${counts.errors}&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;System Errors&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card fails&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;${counts.failedSSH}&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;SSH Failures&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card success&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;${counts.successSSH}&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;SSH Logins&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card kernel&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;${counts.kernel}&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Kernel Warnings&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card network&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;${counts.network}&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;label&quot;&gt;Network Connections&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
  ${renderSection(&quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;, data[&quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;], colors[&quot;System Errors and Warnings&quot;])}
  ${renderSection(&quot;Failed SSH Login Attempts&quot;, data[&quot;Failed SSH Login Attempts&quot;], colors[&quot;Failed SSH Login Attempts&quot;])}
  ${renderSection(&quot;Successful SSH Logins&quot;, data[&quot;Successful SSH Logins&quot;], colors[&quot;Successful SSH Logins&quot;])}
  ${renderSection(&quot;Kernel Warnings&quot;, data[&quot;Kernel Warnings&quot;], colors[&quot;Kernel Warnings&quot;])}
  ${renderSection(&quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;, data[&quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;], colors[&quot;Network Connection Attempts&quot;])}
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;Generated via n8n &#x2022; ${now}&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
`;

return [
  {
    binary: {
      data: await this.helpers.prepareBinaryData(
        Buffer.from(html, &quot;utf8&quot;),
        &quot;system_log_dashboard.html&quot;,
        &quot;text/html&quot;
      ),
    },
  },
];
</code></pre><p>Then I introduced a lightweight <strong>If node</strong> to detect failed SSH login attempts. Using a simple regex check, the workflow looks for numbers under the &#x201C;Failed SSH Login Attempts&#x201D; section and triggers a notification only when something new appears. When paired with an <strong>Ntfy node</strong>, it quietly sends alerts straight to my phone or desktop whenever there&#x2019;s suspicious activity.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/ntfy-n8n-alert-noted.png" class="kg-image" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n" loading="lazy" width="1621" height="837" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/ntfy-n8n-alert-noted.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/ntfy-n8n-alert-noted.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/ntfy-n8n-alert-noted.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/ntfy-n8n-alert-noted.png 1621w"></figure><p>The end result is a practical workflow that not only tracks what&#x2019;s going on with my system but keeps me informed in real time. You can download the full n8n JSON workflow here.</p><div class="kg-card kg-file-card"><a class="kg-file-card-container" href="https://noted.lol/content/files/2025/10/Daily-System-Log-Summary.json" title="Download" download><div class="kg-file-card-contents"><div class="kg-file-card-title">Daily System Log Summary</div><div class="kg-file-card-caption"></div><div class="kg-file-card-metadata"><div class="kg-file-card-filename">Daily System Log Summary.json</div><div class="kg-file-card-filesize">13 KB</div></div></div><div class="kg-file-card-icon"><svg viewbox="0 0 24 24"><defs><style>.a{fill:none;stroke:currentColor;stroke-linecap:round;stroke-linejoin:round;stroke-width:1.5px;}</style></defs><title>download-circle</title><polyline class="a" points="8.25 14.25 12 18 15.75 14.25"/><line class="a" x1="12" y1="6.75" x2="12" y2="18"/><circle class="a" cx="12" cy="12" r="11.25"/></svg></div></a></div><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>If you already use n8n for automation, adding a system health dashboard like this is an easy upgrade that gives you real visibility. You can expand it to watch containers, track disk usage, or send scheduled reports automatically.</p><p>Sometimes the best tools are the ones you build yourself, piece by piece, and this one does exactly what I need without getting in the way.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">An Introduction to n8n for Self-Hosted Labs</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">n8n makes it easy to automate tasks and connect your tools in a self-hosted environment. Here&#x2019;s a beginner-friendly look at what it can do and how it fits into a homelab.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-29.png" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8n-self-hosted-for-beginners-1.png" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure><p>And more here</p><figure class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a class="kg-bookmark-container" href="https://noted.lol/tag/n8n/"><div class="kg-bookmark-content"><div class="kg-bookmark-title">n8n - Noted</div><div class="kg-bookmark-description">I&#x2019;m obsessed with n8n so I made it a category. Here&#x2019;s all things related to n8n.</div><div class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img class="kg-bookmark-icon" src="https://noted.lol/content/images/icon/Icon-1.2-1-33.png" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n"><span class="kg-bookmark-author">Noted</span><span class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Jeremy</span></div></div><div class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/thumbnail/n8-systemlog-workflow-2.png" alt="Building a Simple System Log Dashboard and Alert Workflow with n8n" onerror="this.style.display = &apos;none&apos;"></div></a></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Self-Host Tududi for Smarter Project Management]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tududi is a simple, self-hosted task manager built for developers who want privacy and focus without the noise of modern productivity apps.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/tududi/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f4e47068607e00017bf220</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Task Management & To-do Lists]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:28:53 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-task-management.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-task-management.png" alt="How to Self-Host Tududi for Smarter Project Management"><p>Developers spend so much time organizing other people&#x2019;s systems that their own often fall apart. Tududi is a reminder that productivity tools don&#x2019;t need to be flashy or tied to a subscription to work well. It&#x2019;s a small, open-source task manager that you can run on your own server, built with the kind of simplicity that developers actually appreciate. You spin it up in Docker, log in, and start building structure around your work without fighting the interface. It feels more like software written by someone who codes than someone who markets.</p><h3 id="what-is-tududi">What is Tududi?</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/chrisvel/tududi?ref=noted.lol">Tududi</a> is a self-hosted task and project manager made for people who want to stay organized and keep full control of their data. It runs easily in Docker and stores everything locally. The layout uses areas, projects, and tasks so you can keep work and personal goals in order. It includes recurring tasks, notes, and tags in a clean interface that works on any device. Tududi keeps things simple, private, and reliable for developers who like to manage their own tools.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-to-do.png" class="kg-image" alt="How to Self-Host Tududi for Smarter Project Management" loading="lazy" width="2000" height="1059" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-to-do.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-to-do.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-to-do.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w2400/2025/10/tududi-self-hosted-to-do.png 2400w"></figure><h3 id="core-features-of-tududi">Core Features of Tududi</h3><p><strong>Areas, Projects, and Tasks</strong><br>Tududi organizes everything in three levels. Areas represent broad categories like Work, Home, or Learning. Each area contains projects, and each project holds tasks and subtasks. It keeps structure without feeling heavy.</p><p><strong>Recurring Tasks</strong><br>You can set tasks to repeat daily, weekly, monthly, or after completion. If you finish a recurring task late, the next one still repeats correctly based on the actual completion date.</p><p><strong>Priorities and Tags</strong><br>Every task can have a priority level and one or more tags. Tags help you group or filter tasks across different projects so you can focus on what matters most.</p><p><strong>Due Dates and Sorting</strong><br>Tududi helps you stay on top of deadlines with clear due dates and color indicators. You can sort by date, priority, or project to quickly see what needs attention.</p><p><strong>Subtasks and Progress Tracking</strong><br>Large tasks can be broken down into subtasks, and the app automatically tracks progress as you complete them. It is useful for development cycles or long projects.</p><p><strong>Project Notes</strong><br>Each project has its own notes section where you can keep related information such as code snippets, documentation, or ideas. Notes support formatting and stay linked to the right project.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/tududi-note-mobile-all-dark.png" class="kg-image" alt="How to Self-Host Tududi for Smarter Project Management" loading="lazy" width="780" height="1376" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/tududi-note-mobile-all-dark.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/tududi-note-mobile-all-dark.png 780w"></figure><p><strong>Filtering and Search</strong><br>You can filter tasks by tag, status, or due date and use search to find items quickly. This is especially helpful once your list grows large.</p><p><strong>Multi Language Support</strong><br>Tududi includes translations for more than twenty languages so the interface can match your preferred language.</p><p><strong>Telegram Integration</strong><br>Tasks can be added through Telegram and you can receive daily reminders directly in chat. It is a convenient option for mobile use without needing a separate app.</p><p><strong>Responsive Interface</strong><br>The interface works on desktop, tablet, and mobile browsers. It supports dark and light themes and automatically adjusts to your system setting.</p><p><strong>Self-Hosted Privacy</strong><br>Everything runs on your own server. No cloud storage or third party access. You control the data, backups, and updates.</p><p><strong>Collaboration</strong><br>Projects can be shared with other users on your instance. You can assign tasks or give read only access, making it useful for small teams or family projects.</p><h4 id="installing-tududi-with-docker-compose">Installing Tududi with Docker Compose</h4><p>Tududi runs inside Docker, so installation is simple. The image is available on Docker Hub, and everything such as the database, uploads, and user accounts stays in your local volumes.</p><pre><code class="language-yaml">services:
  tududi:
    image: chrisvel/tududi:latest
    container_name: tududi
    restart: unless-stopped
    ports:
      - &quot;3002:3002&quot;
    environment:
      TUDUDI_USER_EMAIL: you@example.com
      TUDUDI_USER_PASSWORD: yourpassword
      TUDUDI_SESSION_SECRET: replace_with_random_hex
      TUDUDI_ALLOWED_ORIGINS: &quot;http://tududi:3002&quot;
    volumes:
      - /docker/tududi/tududi_db:/app/backend/db
      - /docker/tududi/tududi_uploads:/app/backend/uploads
</code></pre><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>After using Tududi for a while it feels calm and dependable. It does not try to change how you work or demand attention. It gives you a simple space to plan, track, and finish what you start. The more you use it the easier it becomes to stay organized without thinking about it. It is steady and practical software made to help you get things done and then quietly step aside. Be sure to check out the Tududi<a href="https://github.com/chrisvel/tududi?ref=noted.lol" rel="noreferrer"> Github repo</a> and give it a star!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing Networking Toolbox: Self-Hosted Network Tools in One Place]]></title><description><![CDATA[Networking Toolbox is a self-hosted collection of 100+ network utilities that run offline, giving you quick access to IP, DNS, and HTTP tools in one simple web app.]]></description><link>https://noted.lol/networking-toolbox/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68f4d2ea68607e00017be6af</guid><category><![CDATA[Self Hosted Web Tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:27:34 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/netorking-toolbox-self-hosted.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div style="text-align: center;">
  <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/pikapods-banner-v3.webp" alt="Introducing Networking Toolbox: Self-Hosted Network Tools in One Place">
  </a>
  <div style="margin-top: 10px;">
    <strong>SPONSORED BY</strong> <a href="https://pikapods.com/?utm_source=noted.lol" target="_blank">PikaPods</a>
  </div>
</div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/netorking-toolbox-self-hosted.png" alt="Introducing Networking Toolbox: Self-Hosted Network Tools in One Place"><p>If you manage servers or troubleshoot networks, you know how messy it gets keeping all your tools organized. You open ten tabs for DNS lookups, pings, port checks, and IP calculations, then repeat the process the next time something breaks.</p><h3 id="what-is-networking-toolbox">What is Networking Toolbox?</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/Lissy93/networking-toolbox?ref=noted.lol">Networking Toolbox</a> is a free open source web app from the developer behind <a href="https://github.com/Lissy93/dashy?ref=noted.lol">Dashy</a> and other well known self hosted projects. It brings together more than a hundred networking tools in one clean interface. You can host it yourself, use it offline, and handle everything from DNS lookups to IP calculations without switching between sites.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-full"><img src="https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/self-hosted-networking-toolbox.png" class="kg-image" alt="Introducing Networking Toolbox: Self-Hosted Network Tools in One Place" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="916" srcset="https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w600/2025/10/self-hosted-networking-toolbox.png 600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1000/2025/10/self-hosted-networking-toolbox.png 1000w, https://noted.lol/content/images/size/w1600/2025/10/self-hosted-networking-toolbox.png 1600w, https://noted.lol/content/images/2025/10/self-hosted-networking-toolbox.png 1920w"></figure><p><br>I first came across Networking Toolbox while browsing r/selfhosted on Reddit. It immediately caught my attention because it brings so many useful tools together in one place.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><blockquote class="reddit-embed-bq" style="height:500px">
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1o8xm3z/offlinefirst_collection_of_100_networking_tools/?ref=noted.lol">Offline-first collection of 100+ networking tools and utils</a><br> by
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/lissy93/?ref=noted.lol">u/lissy93</a> in
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/?ref=noted.lol">selfhosted</a>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://embed.reddit.com/widgets.js" charset="UTF-8"></script></figure><p>Because it works offline and doesn&#x2019;t depend on third party services when self hosted, it&#x2019;s especially useful in air gapped environments or places where you can&#x2019;t rely on external web tools.</p><h3 id="key-features">Key Features</h3><p>Here are some of the key features of Networking Toolbox:</p><ul><li>Supports self-hosting via Docker, static build or integration in a broader stack.</li><li>Works offline &#x2013; full diagnostics without needing external APIs or internet dependency.</li><li>Includes hundreds of individual tools covering IP/subnet math, DNS/TLS/HTTP diagnostics, conversion utilities and more.</li><li>Custom branding, theming and multi-language support if you deploy it yourself. <a href="https://github.com/Lissy93/networking-toolbox?utm_source=chatgpt.com" rel="noopener">GitHub</a></li></ul><hr><h3 id="deployment-usage">Deployment &amp; Usage</h3><p>Getting started is simple:</p><ol><li>Use Docker: <code>docker run -p 8080:80 lissy93/networking-toolbox</code> (or choose a version tag)</li><li>Build from source: Clone the repo, install dependencies, and run build commands (supports Node, static, Docker, etc)</li></ol><h3 id="final-notes-and-thoughts">Final Notes and Thoughts</h3><p>I found Networking Toolbox to be one of those tools that immediately feels useful. If you spend time working on subnets, DNS issues or HTTP/TLS diagnostics, having everything in one offline-capable package means less context switching and fewer browser tabs.<br><br>It&#x2019;s still evolving but already stable and polished. If you like having tools you control, especially in self-hosted or isolated environments, be sure to check out the <a href="https://github.com/Lissy93/networking-toolbox?ref=noted.lol">Networking Toolbox Github repo</a> and give it a star!</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>
